David S. Kong: Would be great.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's been a minute, so just to do a quick recap from the very beginning.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the five of you, knowing each other and having run various jobs together, got recruited by a,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A sort of a strange, pale… A thick guy in Toland.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To come and help his master.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Clear out or secure his deed to a house in the wilderness, more or less.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Traveling through more and more remote wilderness, you get there to Dandelion House, which is a relic of the Drencorian Empire, magically preserved in some ways, not perfectly preserved.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And is this sort of gorgeous masterpiece of, late Drancorian architecture way far north from the Empire, or maybe towards the northern edges of the Empire.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hulda is the second son of a minor noble who never really inherited or amounted to anything, and always felt like he was
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Owed more and wanted more.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And deep in the throes of a midlife crisis last spring after having killed Dragon and had, you know, done all of these accomplishments, and discovering himself no better off than he'd ever been.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): An elf met with him and gave him the deed to this house, naming him very specifically that he was inherited of it, assuming he could go through the door in the basement and break the treaty set with the man on the other side of the door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With the person on the other side of the door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He sends you through that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): door in the basement below the basement, climbing through this route, and you emerge in the Feywild.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In a sort of a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): skeletal version of that same house? Like, a reflection of it, made of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Bone, or coral, or tree roots, something like that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Heading down the road after passing some dead bodies with their heads either destroyed or removed one way or another.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You make your way to the party of Lord Endlessly, ending a perpetually just-past-its-peak party that's starting to come apart, and after meeting and talking with various inhabitants.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You realize that Lord Ending has, made a commitment with his next neighbor down the road that every time the grandfather clock they gave him strikes zero.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He will send a mortal through the door and into that house.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which is all he says about what it is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… He doesn't like that he made this bargain. He feels like he was tricked into it in a game of naming by a human wizard.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tim, the session notes may be an error here. It was Thalestria, the head of the, order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Who tricked him into it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And she's the head of Erythromus lamparum, and after talking with Menestheus, a mathematician and mapmaker who has been,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sleeping off a drunk at that party for what looks like about 700 years.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The order was charged with… Controlling, containing…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): healing, walling up, or otherwise worrying, in general, about the holes in the universe, the holes between the planes and things that might come through them. A thing, probably, that you all, as players.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Understand maybe more clearly or concretely than, the characters do.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): menestius wasn't a whole lot of use about what exactly they were doing or being contained.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He was, and.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Essentially charged with…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): keeping track of where the map to all of the holes in reality are, the holes between the different planes. And that's what he was doing. He came to the endlessly ending party with, before it was ending, with a couple of dozen other members of his order who made the agreement, but he who had
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A drink or a few too many and fell asleep in the library has been there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the whole time since.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As you head out and down the road, or head out to the gate of Lord Endless the Ending,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You hear the clock strike zero again, and he, Menestheus, is the one crossing the lawn and heading out. You talk with him for a few minutes before accompanying him down the road.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This door is off to the left as you're traveling sort of north, up the road, and maybe then turning left.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Onto this footpath that grows smaller and less finished, and the land rises up until, at the end of it, you find yourself on a sort of a promontory, maybe…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, 100 or 150 feet, with cliffs and rock falling sharply on all sides, down to the bottom of a ravine where, in the shadow of,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the evening, it's just utter darkness at the bottom of it. You can't see it at all.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In front of you, though, is the door with the owl familiar who's scouted ahead, perched on top of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): just like all of us going to our 30th reunion, you know you have already gone through the door in the future, because Lord Ending allowed you to leave the party, and that was a condition of it. So, you know you're going through it at some point.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not that that automatically means you're rushing through right at the moment.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I'd love to do just as sort of table setting first, like, are there other details that I'm missing in that recap that were important to any of you or that stood out?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Things that are worth lifting up.
Eric Rosenbaum: There was definitely a tiger guy.
Mike: I was gonna mention the Vershaka.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, and.
Mike: shotgun, whatever is whatever you have.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Rakshasa had sussed out the story of how this bargain came to be and shared it with you.
David S. Kong: What was…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): probably making his retreat right now, since I don't know… I think there's just those two halflings left at the party by now.
David S. Kong: Who've been there for, like, thousands.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A long, long stretch.
Mike: We never really determined if there was anybody new at the party, did we?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When you say new, what do you mean.
Mike: All the mortals seemed quite old.
David S. Kong: We were new. We're the newest.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You were the newest. There wasn't anyone. Yeah, there wasn't anyone recent, right?
Mike: But I mean, it was like hundreds of years, right? Like there wasn't anybody from.
Mike: 1420, as far as we knew.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is true though. It's not obvious how many mortals have been sent away and what.
Mike: Yay!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, but yeah, yeah, yeah, you're right.
Mike: But that actually makes me wonder too, did we like ever establish some kind of order?
Mike: Like, the guy who was sent away just before us, Was.
Mike: I forget, do we know any details about him?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think it was a human woman, I think.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I should look back at the transcript.
Mike: Yeah, we should just.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You saw it going across the room. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mike: Yeah, okay.
Kate Sackton: Could have been there for 700 years. She could have been there for like.
Mike: Right.
Mike: But we don't know what the order isn't necessarily… I mean, people might have arrived
Mike: at the party in a different order than when they left Talgar.
Mike: We don't really know. Yeah, okay.
David S. Kong: And so, sorry, and where… I remember we were trying to leave the party.
David S. Kong: And then, what's the deal with this, like, what's the deal with this door? Are we like, oh shit, what the fuck is this? Or is this like, what's the… do we know what's behind the door? I'm forgetting. I think I fell asleep at the end of the last episode.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think, and someone else correct or elaborate on this if it's wrong, that you were under the impression that
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In this house, there was a way to get back home again, that there was, like, another route for you all to get back home.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Am I remembering that right, though?
Mike: I don't remember that per se. I remember something about keys.
Kate Sackton: I mean, I think we thought.
Kate Sackton: This.
Eric Rosenbaum: A glass key? A crystal key?
Kate Sackton: Oh, yeah, well, that there's a thing that is in there that if we bring it back to
Kate Sackton: So here's the two things I know.
Kate Sackton: if… there's a thing that's in there that if we bring it back to Lord Endlessly ending.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct.
Kate Sackton: He can break his contract.
Kate Sackton: and stop this whole system from perpetuating, where the door rings, and the mathematical cult people get their sacrifice, and then that person gets, who knows what, sent back home to Talgar!
Kate Sackton: And… and you send your horses out to pasture, and they live on a farm in the West. Like, so that's… that's the degree of confidence that I have with this, like… I mean, yes, they truly are world-traveling…
Kate Sackton: wormhole stopping.
Kate Sackton: advanced sorcerer type people. I believe that the math is the math is there, but I don't know if
Kate Sackton: what all that happens when you leave Lord Endlessly Ending's party is that you get to go back to where you want to go at what time you want to go there.
Eric Rosenbaum: It, like…
Kate Sackton: your own realm in your own place or if you just get used to siphon off some sort of interdimensional travel energy and you get zapped to
Kate Sackton: dimension Z at time y and or you die. I like. I don't know what this other way of getting home is.
Kate Sackton: Because the only person we know came back from this party
Kate Sackton: went back through the really creepy tunnel and came back through the door he left propped open.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right.
David S. Kong: was Diamond.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Just to recap, so the Lord Endless offered you that if you would bring him
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The… he says, in the center of the house is a room, the 27th room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): whose walls are made of cold iron, older than twilight, locked with a glass key. Through certain portents, I have divined that if the key is returned to me and I break it, the bargain will be undone. So he asked if you would do that, and you did not commit to that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it is.
Mike: Kind of weasel.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's an offer on the table, yeah.
Mike: Right.
David S. Kong: Oh, I remember freestyling.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: You're the chair.
David S. Kong: Poetry thing.
Mike: Oh, yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: That was with the.
David S. Kong: Cool. Oh, with that recording?
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, no.
Mike: No, that was with Lord Ensley ending. We had a whole interaction where he asked us about our gifts, and we all kind of made up some bullshitty things about gifts.
Mike: And he was, like, half pleased and half like, do you guys understand the word gift? It means giving me something of value, not this bullshit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But then he did… he gave you a sonnet at the very end. Yeah. I sort of feel like Faye have to speak in iambic pentameter sooner or later.
Mike: Right, right.
David S. Kong: Makes sense.
David S. Kong: Okay, so summarize.
David S. Kong: We are now gonna potentially go… Okay.
David S. Kong: What do we think is behind this door?
Mike: Well, it's, it's this other, it's this, it's where, it's where, what's the, the,
David S. Kong: Lord Endless and Lord his rivals place?
Mike: Yeah.
David S. Kong: Where the glass key is.
Mike: Yes.
Tim Sackton: Yes.
Tim Sackton: Glaski, possibly another exit from the Feywild, possibly this woman who is the head of this order.
Mike: Possibly our deaths.
Tim Sackton: originally tricked him.
Eric Rosenbaum: Now, I have a question.
Eric Rosenbaum: What about rooms 1 through 26?
Eric Rosenbaum: Like, what does it mean that it's the 27.
Kate Sackton: Yes. In what order? Will there be only one order? You can go through them so you know which one is the 27th?
David S. Kong: I think they're, like, airport lounges, personally. I was just at the air… I was just in, like, a fucking huge-ass airport, and I was like.
Eric Rosenbaum: There you go.
David S. Kong: But the other ones are just like, you know, baby changing room.
David S. Kong: Smoking room.
Kate Sackton: I mean, part of what we could do is observe the…
Kate Sackton: Life and times of this poor math guy who's.
Kate Sackton: been selected by the clock tolling and sent.
Kate Sackton: As a mortal.
Kate Sackton: to this destination. So if we follow him and, like, Somebody grabs him and…
Kate Sackton: Nails him sideways to an apparatus and then he dies painfully, you know, we could.
Kate Sackton: You know, that's what happens.
Eric Rosenbaum: We know where he is.
Eric Rosenbaum: Do we know where he is?
Kate Sackton: Speak with us.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep, Menestius is with you.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Eric Rosenbaum: Got it.
Kate Sackton: We sort of made friends, walked together.
Eric Rosenbaum: He can go first, you're saying.
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Kate Sackton: And I forget what was his attitude toward this like? Did he? Suddenly, when we told him where he was going, and this was all connected to the work he used to do. Did he suddenly be like, Oh, or is he just like, I guess this is what I'm doing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, he, he,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I feel like his vibes… I… you all would be closer to this than me, but, like, his vibes are…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Postdoc who has just signed on to a very long contract in a place that turns out to be terrible.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, like, a little disillusioned, a little,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): disappointed. Like, he definitely just put his head in his hands for several minutes and, like, cursed to himself when finding out what the timeline was.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): he was… I… your impression of him was he's totally committed to the mission of the Order. Like, he's… he was totally on board with what they were doing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But also, he was so deep in his own niche that, you know, he doesn't… he doesn't even have, like, a 300-foot view, let alone, like, a 30,000-foot view.
Kate Sackton: So he doesn't know enough to be either scared or reassured. He's just like, well, whatever the mission needs, but this has been not what I wanted.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think so, and I think, like, the 700-year time jump, like, he's still in shock. Like, he… there's no way for him to comprehend it, and also, like, the world around him in the Feywilds is exactly the same.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's still not quite real.
David S. Kong: Sorry, what's the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Erythrimos Lamparum is a Drancorian society that had existed for hundreds of years.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: whose job was to sort of police the boundaries between worlds.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I feel a little strange saying this since it's Tim who wrote it all, but apparently one of the things that Drencor worried about a great deal was like extraplanar threats. And so this was one of the societies or groups who worried about that, kept track of them.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
David S. Kong: And wait, have we met anybody from that or.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menesthe.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, the guy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So the mathematician guy.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, okay, so I think I missed all this, this part Who do we meet?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, Menestheus the Mathematician, as a member of this order, And he…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He had a convoluted thing about how you can hide coordinates.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: within very large semi-prime numbers.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh yeah.
David S. Kong: Oh, yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: Brilliant numbers.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, exactly. Brilliant numbers with two prime factors that give you… Right. Anyways, it's a way of sort of publicly talking about secret things.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's like a kind of a.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then we gave it back to him.
David S. Kong: Oh, I remember, oh yeah, yeah, yeah, he had his book, he.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, the book. Yeah, there was a situation there.
Kate Sackton: I read with.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Don't work out. … but didn't comprehend because math.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah. Very cool.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, to set the table a little bit, standing in front of the door on this, on this bluff that falls away now on three sides.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: In the twilight.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the Twilight 2, which has this funny characteristic that it doesn't seem still, it seems like it is actively growing darker, even though it isn't.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Standing in front of the door.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Can you do a reset of, like, What do you each…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): look like? What are you holding in your hands, if anything?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What is like your internal state? Is this exciting, terrifying?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mystifying, disturbing, like what' What do you look like? What's the.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So Chao is a six foot tall.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Maybe a little bit more than 6 foot tall.
Tim Sackton: Lizard folk, man.
David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: Bluish-green scales, along his face and surrounding his eyes and running down his neck, and along his hands with a sort of more pale yellow.
Tim Sackton: Throat and, the sort of underside of his jaw.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: He wears… relatively simple traveling clothes, a sort of greenish-gray cloak.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Doesn't carry much, except for a…
Tim Sackton: A wooden shield that's… that's strapped to his back that has…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: A.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Tim Sackton: That has like a painted design on the front.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: I think some birds, I forget what I said last time.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Tim Sackton: And, you know, a backpack, basically, with just simple gear.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: on it, and…
Tim Sackton: a…
Tim Sackton: carved, wooden wand that you have heard produced the sound of loons and other birds over your adventuring career, at his, stuck into a little…
Tim Sackton: slot on his wide leather belt that he wears around his waist.
Tim Sackton: He is,
Tim Sackton: Not exactly nervous. He's… he's… A little annoyed with this whole situation, like…
Tim Sackton: Why did we get tricked into this deal with this guy?
Tim Sackton: And now, a little bit uncertain as to…
Tim Sackton: Whether he wants to break the bargain, because
Tim Sackton: The… what was his name? The…
Tim Sackton: I know you just said it, the guy who gave us the deal to begin with.
Kate Sackton: Ortolda?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hold on. Yep.
Tim Sackton: Lord told her, like, Chara was a bit, dubious of Laura Golda.
Tim Sackton: Since the betrayal.
Tim Sackton: So mostly just wants to go home at this point.
Tim Sackton: And is sort of watching the door a little.
Tim Sackton: Prepondentiously wondering what's gonna happen.
Tim Sackton: And watching… Menenthes?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menestheus.
Tim Sackton: Menestheus, Menestheus, see what he will do.
Kate Sackton: You're bird, right?
Tim Sackton: The owl is my familiar.
Kate Sackton: The owl followed another person here. They've been sitting here the entire time.
Tim Sackton: For a while, yes.
Kate Sackton: Did you communicate with the owl in any way to figure out?
Kate Sackton: If it saw anything else, anybody leave, anybody walk past, anything at all other than that, the two people we know, or was it just a…
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Kate Sackton: Because the one person we know went there and went straight in, and then this guy showed up and went straight in.
Tim Sackton: I can ask it.
Kate Sackton: Okay, we haven't gotten there yet.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Nothing. Yeah, that's correct. Nothing except seeing the person go in.
Mike: Edric is… Call.
Mike: Big guy.
Mike: Kind of a… misshapen… Face.
Mike: Slightly… Ugly. Wearing this… sort of gleaming breastplate with a prominent set of…
Mike: stars forming a crown, which is the sign of the Night Queen, and with a massive
Mike: Two-handed maul, slung over his back.
Mike: Not like a big warhammer type thing swung over his back that he's currently reaching back to take out and then thinking better of it and then kind of thinking like he's indecisively trying to decide whether he should be holding his weapon in a ready to smash position or whether that's a bad idea.
Mike: At the same time, he's,
Mike: sort of muttering a prayer, you can't really make out the words, but you can tell when he's sort of muttering under his… or you know him well enough to know when he's standing there kind of muttering under his breath. It's usually some sort of prayer.
Mike: And he looks…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Determined? Like, he… he… He wants to…
Mike: Move forward with this and, like, get on to the next thing.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But…
Mike: He's also a bit…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Mike: He looks out of his depth.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Right? Like, usually, he's used to, kind of.
Mike: Knowing what the safe thing to hit is.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And… Is a little uncomfortable with politics and the.
Mike: constant, sort of…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: discussion about things and there doesn't seem to be a right path.
Mike: Through this, exactly.
Mike: And…
Mike: makes him a little uncomfortable. But going to a scary place actually kind of evens his cue a little bit, right? Like, he's a little bit like, maybe there'll be something here that I can just, like… that party was a little, like, I don't know what's going on here. Maybe there'll be, like, a bad guy will jump out, and I'll be able to just hit it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I love that the party is scarier than a monster.
Mike: Oh, it's way scarier than a mon.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Terry.
Eric Rosenbaum: is a… Slight.
Eric Rosenbaum: Youth with unruly black hair, wearing a… Beat up.
Eric Rosenbaum: But once fine.
Eric Rosenbaum: Cloak.
Eric Rosenbaum: Moves about silently.
Eric Rosenbaum: You catch him occasionally out of the corner of your eye, and he's… In the dim light.
Eric Rosenbaum: Peeking into a inner pocket of his cloak, and sort of…
Eric Rosenbaum: Pulling something palm-sized out, chuckling, putting it back in.
Eric Rosenbaum: And he seems a bit antsy.
Eric Rosenbaum: He finds a suitably sized stone.
Eric Rosenbaum: And deftly hunts it with his toe.
Eric Rosenbaum: Off the edge of the escarpment.
Eric Rosenbaum: Just so as to find out what happens.
David S. Kong: Cato, wearing his long, red,
David S. Kong: Tall and red.
David S. Kong: Travel robe.
David S. Kong: But it's, you know, kind of gold…
David S. Kong: Gold patterns on it, and, little…
David S. Kong: Not travel-worn after the days, or however long we've been out here. Long, golden hair.
David S. Kong: And.
David S. Kong: currently not tied back. So just kind of flowing in the wind.
David S. Kong: And, you know, leaning over… Eric, what's your character's name again?
Eric Rosenbaum: Tarek.
David S. Kong: Tarek, leaning over Tarek's shoulder to like watch this like stone just like bound down the cliff.
David S. Kong: And as you all know, I mean, Cato… Cato's like… Kato's an elf. He's old.
David S. Kong: older than y'all, but also, like, weirdly… kind of immature, and also just…
David S. Kong: kind of emotionally volatile, like, sometimes he's, like, so excited about this treasure, sometimes he's like, we're all gonna die, sometimes he's like, oh, I love this party, sometimes he's like, you know, he's kind of a little emotionally volatile.
David S. Kong: And as president of the state.
David S. Kong: He's leaning into his elf, his inner elf right now, and is sort of, like, kind of resigning himself, like, man, you know…
David S. Kong: How long do elves live?
Tim Sackton: As long as they want to.
David S. Kong: Are they imm.
Mike: Usually 500 to what, 700 years?
David S. Kong: But do you do? I'll do. I'll observe or die of old.
Tim Sackton: They… So…
Tim Sackton: every… so they have the cycle of generations, right? So each time the cycle turns over, which is about 150 years, they typically… I think it's about 150 years… they typically are…
Tim Sackton: have, like, a weaker and weaker connection to Talgar, and unless they have some reason to stick around, eventually they just… wander off. I'm not sure if it's entirely clear where they go.
David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: Afterlife. Okay. But they don't… They don't age in a normal way.
David S. Kong: So, Kato's kind of leaning into his inner elf, and is sort of like, you know what
David S. Kong: we're here for a couple more hundred years, thousand years, you know, he's just, he's just kind of, like, feeling a little, little resigned to the possibilities, not, not really freaking out, but also kind of like, man.
David S. Kong: Oh, boy, this could be… we might be here for a while.
Kate Sackton: It's been… You know, had her…
Kate Sackton: Nice armor on, still looking fresh and tidy and gleaming, appropriate for a party, appropriate for starting out on an adventure.
Kate Sackton: Just.
Kate Sackton: Her long hair, her instrument on her back,
Kate Sackton: hasn't had a, you know, opportunity to play the lute in a while because they had those musicians at the party who the Lord Endlessly Ending had playing endlessly.
Kate Sackton: And… She's, you know, definitely observed the same thing that Edric has. There's not a clear
Kate Sackton: what do we want out of this? Because we don't necessarily want are better, are…
Kate Sackton: I want to say benefactor, but that's not the word for this entity. We don't.
Kate Sackton: necessarily necessarily want our employer to benefit from our work anymore because of his betrayal. We kind of want Lord Ensley ended ending to benefit because we sort of hit it off with him. But there doesn't seem to be a clear path for that yet. So Avian's just keeping her eye out. She's in a
Kate Sackton: needs more information mode.
Kate Sackton: See, see, see where the… right resolution to all this can be.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menesthesis is a Human man in his later 20s, mid or late 20s.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Dressed in a strange sort of old-fashioned way with, like, knee-length breeches and, soft leather shoes. He has a satchel over one shoulder with, you know, a couple of books in it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And around his belt, and on a sort of a… a bandolier of little pockets and such on the satchel, that the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you know, small pockets and containers that you associate with, spell components. I.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he has a, a knife at his side, like a long sort of dagger knife, but otherwise is unarmed. His ring on his finger… actually, there's a couple of rings on his fingers, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He looks sort of resigned, like,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, this is a person who…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): who fell asleep at a work event, and everyone left without him. So, like, even… even in the best-case scenario, this is not going well for him.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Even if it wasn't 700 years later.
Eric Rosenbaum: Nice.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The door stands in front of you. A light, cool breeze blows.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Still with a scent of warm grass.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What do you do?
Eric Rosenbaum: Did I hit anything with the rock?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You heard it skitter down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A little ways, and then… Lost sight and sound of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, there'.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Perception may have had a different experience.
Eric Rosenbaum: The ravine of endlessly falling.
Tim Sackton: I think we're waiting for… Uhm…
Kate Sackton: Inespis.
Tim Sackton: Menestless to go in, right?
Kate Sackton: Yeah, it's his show.
Tim Sackton: It's this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He looks around, and just sighs, a big, long sigh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well… We're, we're going in then, huh
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm sure this will be fine.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he reaches forward.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Turns the handle on the door, and it opens… Outward, towards you all.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And when he opens it, you can see into this interior room,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): lit by a few lamps in the corner. It's, you know, without going in, there's not too much to see, but it's,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sorry.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): From what you can see, it looks…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): like it was full of stuff that's been smashed up or destroyed. It looks like it's been in pretty bad shape.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you want to go in?
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, yeah. Yes, too.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menestheus looks around to all of you and says, Yeah, alright.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Let's go!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And steps across the threshold and looks back at you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I would love to not do this by myself, but I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I understand if, if y'all can't.
Mike: No, I'll come with you.
Eric Rosenbaum: A stroll forward too.
Kate Sackton: Frederick's so hot now.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As you come into the room,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The room is quite large, and a little bit oddly shaped. It's about 30 feet wide, and about 30 feet deep, and about 30 feet tall. And you see…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): first, it's just sort of a scene of destruction. Like, there were tables and chairs that have been smashed and overturned,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): sort of a counter by the door, that we're just going to assume that comprehend language is up as a ritual indefinitely for the sake of simplicity. You know, that at one point read current occupants and would have had a number below it, but has been smashed apart.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a tapestry, a giant tapestry on one side that's been pulled down and mangled. On the far wall across from the door, so 30 feet in front of you, almost the entire space is taken up with massive
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like… pipes and tubes and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): turbines, stuff made of cast copper and iron, that's almost, I don't know, steam pump looking. There's a hum that comes from all of it, but no, obviously moving parts.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There is a door… so the door that you just walked through is in the center of one wall. There's a door in the center of the left wall, there's a door in the center of the right wall, and there's a staircase in the center of the room that goes up and down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Spiral staircase.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're muted, Eric.
Eric Rosenbaum: Thanks. The occupancy sign, what was the story with that? It would have listed the number of people in the room. Oh, no, the maximum number of people.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no, it looked like it had those little flippy numbers like the clocks did.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So perhaps it might have been a… like a… your guess is that it was a running tally of occupants.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's weird.
Kate Sackton: And presumably, we try opening the door we just came in, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh yeah, it just opens right back out again.
Kate Sackton: Oh, okay, so we…
Kate Sackton: Well, if we're trying to get to room number 27…
Kate Sackton: And we have 4 not necessarily numbered options for leaving this room.
Kate Sackton: The second room that we enter won't necessarily be the 27th room.
Kate Sackton: by any math.
Kate Sackton: You know, if it's random.
Kate Sackton: one-fourth of all the options in the rooms that we start off in, so I don't exactly know how to get to the 27th room, but…
Kate Sackton: I mean, again, let Vanessa's pick.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Look, I don't actually know where we're going. This is as far as I've ever gotten in the house
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We came in, and I met up with the rest of the crew, and they were already on the way out, like, I'm…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I… I know where we are, but I don't know… I… I mean…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I know where we are in space.
Eric Rosenbaum: What's that big machine over there?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I… He gives an elaborate shrug.
Kate Sackton: do you want to sit here in this room and read your books and hope that this is your life for the rest of your life, is sitting in this room reading your books over and over and again, and maybe or maybe not experiencing hunger? I'm not really sure how that goes.
Kate Sackton: Or do you want to explore?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I do want to stay with you. I, this, this is, this, I, Yeah, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you want to stay here by yourself? No! This is terrible! What happened here? Why is everything destroyed?
Mike: Yeah, I wouldn't want to stay here by myself. That would be scary and weird.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, we this guy gets it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh!
Mike: Bye.
Mike: This doesn't. It took sort of Pat's Pat's small look like a problem.
Mike: I'm not sure how to solve this problem.
Mike: Maybe one of the wiser heads knows what to do.
Mike: Kind of looks around desperately at the rest of the party.
Tim Sackton: I mean, there's no… Well, while they're talking, Chara's just kind of looking around a little bit, just…
Tim Sackton: I mean, there's… there's… there's… What, two doors out of this room?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Two doors, a door to the left, a door to the right, and stairs that.
Tim Sackton: Right. And doors are not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You too.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Looking around is fine. I'll give you details. If you want more, you can do investigation or perception.
Tim Sackton: Ours are… are they… Do they just open? Like, are they locked?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, the doors, on either side, and in fact, when you come over to the stairs and look up, there's a door at the top and a door at the bottom, also, maybe a half a story. The door opens to a narrow corridor that's about 10 feet long, with another door at the far end of it.
Tim Sackton: Like, both doors open to the same location.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All four doors, yep.
Kate Sackton: Presuming we checked all 4 doors, and they all look the same until open them.
Kate Sackton: So it's not one opens to a delicious smelling sort of kitchen, and another one opens to a discotheque room like they're all just
Kate Sackton: tunnels.
Tim Sackton: And there's no markings or footprints or…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Excuse me, thank you, yes. There is a little sign. When you go through the… you open the door, you go into the hall. At the door on the far end of the hall, that door is locked, so you can't open it, and there is a little, sign next to it, that says,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): all members of your group must come through together.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and on the all members of a group must come through together, and then there is a number like a little room number marker on the center of the door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The door to the left is 12, to the right is 16, 4 is up and 22 is down.
David S. Kong: Wait, do these numbers have anything to do with the whole, like, numbers of code for the thing with the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menesthius does not seem to think so.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
David S. Kong: Well, he's a mathematician, I trust him.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I never really did interiors, he said.
Kate Sackton: Oh, 4, 12.
Kate Sackton: 2117 or something? What'd you say?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 12, 16, 4, 22.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, you cannot discern any meaning to those numbers. Sorry.
Tim Sackton: Right. 22 is down.
Tim Sackton: 12 is left.
Tim Sackton: 4 is right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): For us.
Tim Sackton: for.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And 16 is right.
Tim Sackton: 22 is closest to 27. Let's go that way.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, that's what I was thinking, too. I want to look at this machine first, though I'm curious about it.
Eric Rosenbaum: What should I roll?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Why don't you do investigation?
Eric Rosenbaum: And.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, that's an 8 total.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's big.
Eric Rosenbaum: I mean, it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's impressive looking.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's not just decoration. When you put your hand on it, you can feel, like, the hum of something.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And maybe even a little bit of, like, static electricity or, like, a little smell of ozone or something like that, but,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can't make heads or tails of what it'.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's weird.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, let's go to 22.
Eric Rosenbaum: That was… Downstairs?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 22. Awesome.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You go down the stairs to 22.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 22… so, you go down the stairs, you go into the little corridor, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The door at the far end of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): is locked until all of you are in the space. You close the door behind you, and then the door on the other side becomes unlocked, and you can all go through it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You come through that door after this little quarter and down the stairs through the continuation of the stairway that comes down through the center of this room. This room is about the same dimensions as the one you were in before. It's maybe 30 by 30 and 30 feet tall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and it has exits. You come down the stairs.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And if you're facing the same way you were in the room above, there's an entrance and exit in front of you, and on either of the sides, to your left or right. So you can go back up, or you can go left or right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This room is clearly a chapel.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… actually, I need a little bit of help here, Tim, and what would a Drancorian chapel, like, what gods would be in it?
Tim Sackton: Moss Newman, huh let's… So…
Mike: Same gods.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, same as, like, Sambara.
Tim Sackton: Umm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's not different kind than, like, the chapels that you've been in before, and there are the spaces for the various gods, but the design and the feel of it is really different. It's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): clearly older. It's like going, I don't know, into the Vatican or something, you know, all this sort of smooth, polished marble, you know, with little variegated flecks of color in it, in a way that nobody would build a chapel today.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Even though it's extremely impressive.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Looking around through the space, there's not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there's not much in the way of stuff in it. You know, there's icons or statues, maybe there's art that's devoted to Masnumina, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's not, you know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's sort of the, just the devotional space, there's, there's not much else to it.
Tim Sackton: Are there numbers on the exits from here?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I mean.
Mike: This is a Drancorian chapel with, the Drancorian style was like little alcoves for all the gods, right?
Mike: Tim.
Tim Sackton: Yes, although…
Mike: Probably.
Tim Sackton: Right. Although, conceivably, you might… right.
Tim Sackton: Yes, you would typically have, like, 8 alcoves in a…
Mike: I mean, is this, like, intact with, like, holy symbol? I mean, does it, does.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Y'all can, y'all can investigate.
Mike: I mean, forget even investigating, I'm just, like, looking around. Is the Night Queen's altar recognizably Night Queen's altar?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes, although again, I'm sort of deferring to Tim because I don't know enough about Drankurian theology.
Tim Sackton: So if it's not been intentionally ruined, you would expect to have
Tim Sackton: Like an architectural design that has eight separate alcoves that are physically separated from each other in with some kind of.
Tim Sackton: Depending on how fancy it is, either some, like.
Tim Sackton: you know, elaborate, massive stained glass and, like, you know, jewel-gemmed carving statuary things, or as simple as just, like, a plain sort of
Tim Sackton: curvy wall or whatever, but the idea is that you architecturally isolate the Eight Altars to the Eight Divines, because there is a belief that the
Tim Sackton: that the gods cannot hear you unless you are speaking to them alone, so you don't want your prayer to the Night Queen
Tim Sackton: You want only the Night Queen to hear the prayer to the Night Queen
Tim Sackton: So, if it is intact, you would expect to see 8 separate altars with all 8 of the
Tim Sackton: Mos Numina 8 Divines.
Tim Sackton: represented with the same iconography as is common in modern sambara.
Tim Sackton: There's stylistic differences in the iconic, you know, in the icons and things, but it would be…
Tim Sackton: Clearly recognizable, especially to somebody like, Edric.
Tim Sackton: That said, of course, it could be built intentionally, differently, or partially ruined, in which case some of those
Tim Sackton: alcove and altar spaces might not be present. But that would be the Assumed standard design.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, and that is indeed the design, with one exception. It's not anything that's been destroyed or defaced in any of the spaces for those gods, but
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there's a spot in order to get to the back exit of the room, you have to sort of go around this little corridor that kind of, like, goes around one of the enclosed spaces for the gods. And on the back side of it, where there's just a blank wall headed out that back exit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's like someone has taken a hammer or a pickaxe to the blank wall and just made, like, a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But… Divot? A void? A niche? Maybe? That's about a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): foot or two across and a few feet high, just sort of smashed out from within it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the longer you spend looking at this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's a strange thing, because it's… it's clearly intentional, it's not, you know, it's not like age or something's gone wrong with the masonry, like, someone has smashed this thing out, and it's just an empty n
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Disturbing in a way that's difficult to articulate.
Mike: Well, Aedric is gonna, before even worrying about the disturbing thing, go offer a prayer at the Night Queen's altar.
Mike: And, like, Take a few minutes about it, and like…
Mike: Try and get a sense if this is still.
Mike: consecrated. Is this, is this like, actually still holy and working? Or is this like.
Mike: dead, and you know what I mean? Like, is it, is it a live holy space, or is it dead?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, it definitely is. It definitely is. Inside the… You know, that space.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): presumably the others.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's lovely, it's grounding.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It sets you at ease a little bit.
Mike: Edric will kind of.
Mike: Over his shoulder, say.
Mike: I'm gonna just stay here for a minute, because it's very… but maybe that… someone should go see why that creepy thing is so creepy.
Mike: Pointing at the, like, hole. That seems unnerving.
Eric Rosenbaum: Dark sticks his hand in the hole.
David S. Kong: John from Tarik.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Bye!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Give me a, what's a good save? How about a wisdom save.
Eric Rosenbaum: Gold coins I wish to receive. Oh, a wisdom save. Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's also an eight.
Eric Rosenbaum: In total.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You snatch it right back out again and feel just for a second like you're gonna vomit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it passes.
Eric Rosenbaum: What?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's weird. You're not even conscious of pulling your hand back.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
David S. Kong: Beautiful.
Eric Rosenbaum: Try this. Can you try that?
David S. Kong: I feel like that's kind of a you.
Eric Rosenbaum: No, man.
Eric Rosenbaum: It feels great. You should try it.
Eric Rosenbaum: What?
David S. Kong: Yeah, this is definitely it.
Tim Sackton: Wait, wait, wait, why are we sticking our hand into creepy holes?
Eric Rosenbaum: It's clerical sake.
Mike: I didn't mean do something dumb.
Mike: Like, be safe!
David S. Kong: You've not been around us very long.
Mike: I mean, I mean.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, definitely.
Mike: Fair! I mean, I guess that… I'm sorry, that was not the appropriate word here. It's all good.
David S. Kong: Okay.
Mike: Maybe we should be a little less reckless in this.
Mike: place of uncertainty and… Oddness.
Tim Sackton: Have there been any signs of any other… I was asking about, like, tracks and signs of passage before. Has, like, any indication that anybody else has been in this house anytime recently?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, you don't hear sound, like, and in this room, you can't hear the humming of the machines that were in the entryway. You don't hear footsteps or voices, or it's… it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In fact, when you all slow down, it is like… Perfectly silent.
Eric Rosenbaum: Are there any souvenirs?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, you could steal from one of the… Shrines to the gods?
Mike: No, don't do that.
Kate Sackton: No, no you can't.
Eric Rosenbaum: I consider it carefully, weighing costs and benefits.
David S. Kong: I only see benefits.
Kate Sackton: So in the entryway, it got all wrecked. Like, everything got all wrecked.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Kate Sackton: Here.
Kate Sackton: People have been respectful of the religious sanctity.
Kate Sackton: But in the knot.
Kate Sackton: sanctified space.
Kate Sackton: Somebody also took out some sort of aggression, or… panic, or…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think that's the right way to read the entryway is aggression or panic. I mean, it wasn't like a systematic, it wasn't the way it looks like when a room's been tossed searching for something. It was, yeah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Like a flailing, almost.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But not here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Kate Sackton: But by the divot.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, sorry, about the divot, no, intentional. It looks carved.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Someone made it.
Eric Rosenbaum: What's the height above the floor of the divot?
Kate Sackton: It doesn't look hacked. It looks like nice.
Kate Sackton: Well done.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It looks intentional. I mean, it's… there's something about it that just feels… Mildly disgusting to look at?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which, your thinking mind…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Does not make sense of, because it is just, like, a little niche that someone took a hammer and… or a hammer and chisel, or a… who even knows, and carved it out of the back of a wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But there's something uncomfortable.
Kate Sackton: Oh.
Mike: nauseating or, like, scary.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Both.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes, that's, yeah.
Kate Sackton: All right.
Kate Sackton: Good to know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Four exits, left, right, forward, up.
Tim Sackton: so I was asking before are any of them numbered wait up is back the way we came.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you want to check the numbers on all the doors?
Kate Sackton: Yes, please.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So left is 25.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Forward is, 23.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right is 19?
Tim Sackton: Wait, forward, what does forward mean in this circumstance?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We're gonna assume… That you were facing…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): North, when you entered this building?
Kate Sackton: Sixth quarter.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So like the door went from south to north, you step north to enter it. So forward is north. So we'll do it that way instead. So north, west, east, and up.
Tim Sackton: Okay, so… West is 25.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep, North is.
Tim Sackton: Zora 3 is… 23.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): East is 19.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And up is 17.
Eric Rosenbaum: Wait a minute.
Tim Sackton: Can we just check that?
Tim Sackton: That op takes us back to the room we started in.
Eric Rosenbaum: Abacus.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you all climb up the flight of stairs. You step into the corridor and close the door behind you and open the door in front of you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you are standing…
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, boy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not in the room that you came in.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're standing instead in a room that's filled almost the entire space.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): with this massive mechanical equipment, huge tanks that feed through enormous pipes and go into the north wall of this room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's… there's almost, like, catwalks. The only available space to move is, like, these narrow little corridors that kind of dodge through the immensity of all of this equipment that's all around you.
Tim Sackton: Is this plausibly the… Same room as the other one we were in, but…
Tim Sackton: Back in time. Do we see the occupancy sign on the wall?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, so the other room really… the room that you came in really just had
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the pipes and machinery against the far wall, the north wall, and this… almost this entire space is filled with, machinery, like, arcane machinery.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And as you… if you want to walk around, I can give you the exits and all of that, too.
Eric Rosenbaum: You know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you can go… Up?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Down west or east.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And oddly, against the north wall… There is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you duck under a pipe?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you come out against the far wall, the north wall. There's not an exit there. But what there is is something that's almost like a window, like a 2 foot by 2 foot cutout in the wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you're looking through about, I don't know, 3 feet of stone wall, and on the other side of it, flush against it, as if it's just a recessed back, but you get this distinct impression of being a window, is,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A two-foot square of elaborately inscribed iron wall, with… just covered in runes and arcane markings that you can't decipher.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And right next to it, so you've dodged under this big pipe to come out next to this window thing, there is a chair and a writing desk with a journal on top of it.
Eric Rosenbaum: Let's have a look at that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They seem to be notes, and they are numbered, by date.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With dates that don't…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exactly makes sense, or at least it's a little challenging to do the translation from Dankurian in your head, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's probably about 30 pages or so filled on a small, maybe 4 inch by 6 inch notebook, that comprises 15 or 20 entries, the dates of which seem to be,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you know, some of them are really close back to back, and some of them are farther apart. There's no discernible pattern, to what that looks like. Though the last one is a very long time ago now, so it was…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, 700-some years ago.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it seems to be a transcription of, like, a monologue?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… Ahhh!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it goes something like this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it's in quotes, and it says…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When I get here, I do not know anyone.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But there is a teacher who is very patient with me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He's teaching me about words.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He's teaching me that words have an order. Words have a before and an after.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He says that words are a game to play, because of course there is no such thing as before, and no such thing as after, except that words make it so.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He says that if I am to play games with the dreamers, I am learning about the order of words.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's the first entry, and someone's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Scrawled notes to themselves below it, saying, like, child? Question mark? Timeline? Question mark?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next entry continues, he says, or with another quote, he says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am learning about the order of words.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My teacher teaches me about eating and drinking.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): About sunset and stars. About beginnings and endings.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He teaches me about the danger of cold iron and the fearfulness of the dreamers.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He teaches me that words are letters, and brings me books, and I am reading them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He teaches me about trees, and roots, and leaves, and mushrooms, and houses, and hedges, and roads, and doors. And there's a note below it that says, this list continues in this vein for some time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next entry is a little while later.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It says… This world is strange and scary.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am alone without the teacher.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): His evening is beginning, he tells me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He comes back, he tells me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He is not coming back. He is forgetting me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm not going to him. I'm going past his house. I'm going on and on and on and on. And there's another note below it that says, this continues for some time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The entries go on in this vein, sort of page after page, this odd jumble of things being learned.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A sense of abandonment and fear.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): an almost childish… pride in not needing a teacher anymore.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Though, oddly, it's all written in the present tense
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Until finally, on the last entry, it says, I am grown.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The world is very big.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm tall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I stretch out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My hands are under a very bright and changing sky.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My legs are reaching between trees and roots and leaves and mushrooms and becoming houses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that's the last entry in that.
Kate Sackton: No commentary from the transcriber.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Transcriber has written 3 question marks below this.
Tim Sackton: Book is not fastened down in any way.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no, it's just loose on top of it, yeah.
Tim Sackton: I'll look over it.
Tim Sackton: Alright.
David S. Kong: Wait, but is, is the, there's like, cause there's, there's the original writing of like.
David S. Kong: Does the handwriting change at all over time?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): True that.
David S. Kong: Little kids, kids, and then it gets…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So this is so good. So what's happening is this is a transcription and there's a title page or a record of that.
Tim Sackton: Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): date, and then the name of a person doing the transcribing, and then something to the effect of, like, I heard the following, and then that. So there are a few different people who are doing the transcribing, like people are taking shifts or rotating who's doing it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But the speaker is not the one writing it down. This is something that's been heard.
David S. Kong: I see.
Tim Sackton: I'll just flip to the 27th page and see if there's anything particularly interesting to note there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there's nothing that distinguishes that from the other pages. The world is strange and scary, and I am alone.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My teacher's party is beginning and he will come and he is coming back. He says he is not coming back. He is forgetting me over and over. I'm not going to him. I'm going on.
David S. Kong: So, so the teacher is, the teacher is Lord, Lord Endless.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Presumably.
David S. Kong: Endlessly ending. And then… The student is the person in this house who we have not met yet.
Eric Rosenbaum: I think the student becomes a whole bunch of.
David S. Kong: Did Eric freeze?
Mike: Yes, yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At the most suspenseful possible point in the sentence.
Kate Sackton: It was a great theory. Yeah.
David S. Kong: Eric. Eric. Eric.
Tim Sackton: Oh, becoming houses.
Mike: Oh, interesting.
Mike: It's a creature that becomes houses.
David S. Kong: That's so…
Tim Sackton: I'll pick up the journal, I'll hand it to T.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
Eric Rosenbaum: Not sure it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, we heard you for just a sec, Har
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, looking through the journal, I think maybe another way to say it, too, is it's almost like this is a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, no.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, okay. No, you're all just very still. It's almost like this is a person who's perseverating. They keep coming back to the same things over and over again. And even though when you read those sentences, you have a sense of a progression in time, like there's this idea of a child and then the child has grown.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's all written in the present tense, so, like, the speaker doesn't have that same…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): kind of sensibility. There's not a narrative quality to it. It's just a whole lot of thoughts and statements.
Kate Sackton: And there's a desk here.
Kate Sackton: that faces the weird runic window thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep, exactly. A desk and a ch.
Kate Sackton: So possibly… If this desk is manned.
Kate Sackton: You know, if someone is at this desk for certain amounts of time.
Kate Sackton: They sometimes hear this thing and transcribe it.
Kate Sackton: and make a little note and reflection.
Mike: Oh, wait, you said that it's all different handwriting, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, like different people are transcribing.
David S. Kong: We should do the transcribing. How do we do it?
Kate Sackton: You wanna just sit here and wait until you hear the voice of somebody that turns into a house and like.
David S. Kong: I want it, I want it.
David S. Kong: Who is it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tell me what you're doing, c.
David S. Kong: I wanna interview the person getting turned into a house.
Mike: But are you gonna sit down in the chair?
David S. Kong: Yeah, sit down on the chair.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you're sitting in the chair, nothing's happening immediately.
David S. Kong: Does the, does the, does the, do the, from the other pages, does it all start, does it start in any consistent way, or is it just like somebody starts talking?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, it's just that someone starts talking and it starts in the middle. There's no instruction of like an invocation to say or something.
David S. Kong: date, or something like that, or is there anything like, or is it just like, start
David S. Kong: You know what I mean.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Wait, wait, say that one more time.
David S. Kong: Like, the entries, like, for each entry in the book, does it start with anything consistent? Is there, like, a date? Is there, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah. So there's a date. There's the name of the transcriber, and then it just starts in.
Mike: So there's different names.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
Mike: What are the different like? Are they?
Kate Sackton: They're all different. Are they like.
Mike: wildly different names? Like, does it feel like one's Dunmari and one's… they all drink Corian? Like, what's the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menesthetes says, let him take a look at those for a sec. And he recognizes a couple of those names as members of the Erthrimus Lemperum, as members of his order. Not all of them, but a few of the names he recognizes.
David S. Kong: Are they alive.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In fact, one of them, a couple of them, he says, we… They were… they…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They left me at the house down the road. They left me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fuckers.
David S. Kong: Oh, so these are, like, living people, not, like, historically old people.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, when he says that, he was left there 700 years ago.
David S. Kong: Damn.
David S. Kong: Kato, yeah, Kato will sit down and write Tarek's name.
David S. Kong: First.
David S. Kong: And then…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As far as you can tell, the book's perfectly ordinary. So there it goes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And how… I don't know, tell me about what you're doing. So you're sitting.
David S. Kong: I'm sitting in the chair. I want to start right. I'm just trying to copy the entries just like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): like, Like, you start, like, an automatic writing kind of thing.
David S. Kong: I think like just start.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Start writing.
Eric Rosenbaum: Whoa.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What is an appropriate,
David S. Kong: I have a session, so I'm down.
David S. Kong: Keep Tarek's name initially.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
David S. Kong: him in, and then he puts down what was the date when we…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Very good. Well.
David S. Kong: And then, like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can make, like, a straight wisdom check if you want, or if you have a skill that you think is applicable, you can…
David S. Kong: I have no idea what the fuck this is. Well, I don't even know what I'm doing. I'll… yeah, sure, I
David S. Kong: Awesome.
David S. Kong: 18.
Eric Rosenbaum: Nice.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, plus one is, yeah, yeah, yeah.
David S. Kong: 17 plus 1 is 18.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Umm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With that, You find that you are starting to write down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): fragmentary words. They're not sentences or complete thoughts exactly, but they're sort of in keeping with the stuff that's elsewhere in the book. You know, alone, scary.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): grown… Bright sky.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's, you know, it's, they're just fragments, but
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You are writing down what you think you hear as a whisper.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Coming from the window.
David S. Kong: Anybody else hearing that?
Mike: Anything to.
Tim Sackton: Do I hear anything?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No.
Eric Rosenbaum: Hmmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In fact, as soon as you put the pen down, the whispers stop.
David S. Kong: But,
David S. Kong: Anybody?
Mike: That's how I'm something seems to be.
Mike: That's Which direction, like, the window is… Does it make sense.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The window is north.
Mike: But I mean, has anybody been, I admit that I've been.
Mike: Not totally focused on the map.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you went in, you went down, you went back up again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Although it was a different room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But that' That's.
Mike: I'm just roleplaying Edrick here. He's just like, I'm following you guys, I don't know where we are, and I don't know why the rooms are different. But, so, is it… in theory, maybe it makes sense that it's the outside?
Mike: Like, it's looking out into… Nothing? It's just rooms, right? Can we see anything out the window?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, the window. What you see through the window is a solid wall of iron carved, right? Okay, you said that. It's just a blank, right?
Mike: Fine. Yeah.
David S. Kong: But that's where I heard voices coming through that window.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep, exactly.
David S. Kong: Just the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Barest incomprehensible whispers, yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: I think iron is important.
Eric Rosenbaum: It was mentioned in the transcript as dangerous.
Eric Rosenbaum: Does anybody know, like… what that might tell us about the creatures involved? Like, is anybody vulnerable to… Irony?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They don't like iron.
Eric Rosenbaum: They don't like iron.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that's known at least at the level of fairy tales.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right, right.
Kate Sackton: I… I mean, do you want me to do an Arcana?
Kate Sackton: Check on the subject of any of this.
Eric Rosenbaum: Hold on.
Mike: I will say my impression of Sal Cafe has always been. It's totally unclear if that's a myth or a real thing.
Eric Rosenbaum: I think that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Also true.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, wait, is that actually mentioned anywhere?
Kate Sackton: Is what mentioned where?
Tim Sackton: I thought that, I mean, that's a, that's a common real world myth.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think your player knowledge of the Fae is extremely limited.
David S. Kong: Bye.
Eric Rosenbaum: Character.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You should totally archive that.
Kate Sackton: Bloopity bloopity.
David S. Kong: Oh my god.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Jeez.
Kate Sackton: I rolled 18 and I have a plus four, so 22.
Eric Rosenbaum: Cheers.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You guys are supposed to be third level characters.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm positive.
Tim Sackton: They're really good at skills.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think with an 18, or with a 22… What you know is, But…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): there are some fae that are susceptible to iron, and some aren't. Like, it's not a universal thing, but there are some who fear iron, and your recollection of that, is because there are some…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When creatures are not native to the material plane, certain metals or certain elements can have effects on them that are different.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Than they are on inhabitants to the material plane.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, iron might be dangerous for some fae, it might be dangerous for some other
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Creatures that are not from the material plane.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmh.
Kate Sackton: that are fixated on mushrooms and grow into houses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, which could be a fey, but, you know, who knows?
Eric Rosenbaum: Can we get that grow into houses bit again? That was very interesting.
David S. Kong: Yeah, I missed it.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right at the end there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The last entry is, "I am grown. The world is very big. I am tall. I stretch out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My hands are under a very bright and changing sky.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My legs are reaching between trees and roots and leaves and mushrooms and becoming houses.
Eric Rosenbaum: That is so good and so weird.
Kate Sackton: And there were roots.
Eric Rosenbaum: Do not understand it.
Eric Rosenbaum: But…
Kate Sackton: If we go back down the stairs, if we leave this little fascinating enclave in the pipe room with the desk to the window to the iron.
Tim Sackton: Wait, wait, wait, wait. No, we can't try ourselves. We can't go back down the stairs yet because.
Kate Sackton: I don't want to go through the door, I just want to know if it's labeled 22.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmhm.
Kate Sackton: If it's still lab.
Tim Sackton: Ahhh…
Kate Sackton: It'll be the chapel, and if it's labeled
Kate Sackton: Then I just want to know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, the door at the stairs going down is 20.
Kate Sackton: All right.
Mike: So we need to be making a little map that gives us the keys for each.
Tim Sackton: That's what I'm doing.
Tim Sackton: Sorry, what was… 7… from 17, down is 20.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Tim Sackton: Are there other doors over there?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): West is 16. East is 18.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And up is 8.
Tim Sackton: West is 16?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
Tim Sackton: Wait a minute.
Kate Sackton: Here we go.
Eric Rosenbaum: or something.
Kate Sackton: Meet in the other room.
Tim Sackton: And, and sorry, East is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 18.
Kate Sackton: So we've seen 2 doors for 16, and so far haven't taken either of them.
Tim Sackton: I'm Charles really Charles says we really got to go through 16 to see if it.
Tim Sackton: connects back to… our entry room.
Tim Sackton: 16 was… if we had gone east from the entry room, we would have gotten into 16.
Kate Sackton: You've been presented with the option for 16 twice.
Tim Sackton: So let's go through 16 and see what happens.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fabulous.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right, you go through 16.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And in 16, 16 is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Kitchen and dining room. So it's… it's the similar… it's the same size and shape, the sort of 30x30x30 space. Though in this one, everything is sort of on the… the ground floor, and then there's just a big empty, space of ceiling above.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Excuse me, and about, ahhh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, about a 15 by 20 foot stretch of it along the west wall, which does not have an exit, is devoted to, like, big industrial kitchens that are huge ovens, and prep space, and cabinets, and racks of,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): dishes and cleaning stones and knives and utensils and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): at least a couple of things that you recognize as the same, like, icebox, magical iceboxes, as you saw in Hulda's house. And then most of the rest of the room is given over to dining, so there are two long
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): tables, each with, What is about 2 foot a place, so, maybe,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, 10 or 12 chairs on a side on each of them, room enough for two dozen people to eat pretty easily. The exits from this room are…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Back to the east, the door you came through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To the north?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Up and down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, East is 23, North is 13.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Up is 7, and down is 19.
Tim Sackton: Sorry, east is 23, north is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 13.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Up is 7, and down is 19.
Tim Sackton: But there's no South or West.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No south, no west.
Tim Sackton: Ciao!
Tim Sackton: is gonna go to the West Wall. There's, like, ovens and things on the West Wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
Tim Sackton: I'm just gonna… Push them around it, like…
Tim Sackton: Knock some stuff down in frustration.
Tim Sackton: And then I'm gonna turn to the rest of the party and be like This place makes no sense.
Eric Rosenbaum: Maybe.
Tim Sackton: And then I'm gonna sit down on the floor.
Eric Rosenbaum: True.
David S. Kong: Guy, so what's going on with the numbers? Can you help us? Like, where's 26?
David S. Kong: Nice guy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I, I, I'm, I'm working on it, says Menestheus. I.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am a little hungover, that's… What's the
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think we don't… I,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think we don't have enough data, I… I can't… I don't see.
David S. Kong: What's your highest degree?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hmm. I bet your world doesn't even have it anymore. Hmm.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
David S. Kong: Mmm.
Kate Sackton: Do the magical ice boxes have food in them?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's pickles. There's some deviled eggs that look a little questionable.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a ham, whole ham in one of them.
Eric Rosenbaum: Nice.
Kate Sackton: What is it?
Eric Rosenbaum: What does Charo like to eat? Oh, I can make him.
Kate Sackton: I mean. Pickles improve Charles mood.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So that seems to be it though. Kitchens and dining rooms.
Mike: It's true, it doesn't really make a lot of sense. The rooms seem to be randomly connected to each other.
Mike: Right? Like, there's no… It doesn't… it's not like they seem to.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay, I'll make that.
Mike: Correct.
Eric Rosenbaum: Share your…
Kate Sackton: You'.
Eric Rosenbaum: map image.
Kate Sackton: There's two thoughts.
Kate Sackton: Thought one is we haven't seen any numbers higher than 27 yet.
Kate Sackton: Thought, too, is we keep getting 3 or 4 options per room.
Kate Sackton: So we don't have to go through that many rooms.
Kate Sackton: Before we…
Mike: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: seen all of the numbers, and one of them will maybe be 27, if that's the one we're interested in.
Kate Sackton: We don't know if we're interested in 27. We just want to solve the mystery of.
Mike: There's nothing like a…
Kate Sackton: To do what we have to do in room 27.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menesthius nods in agreement. I If we're gonna figure out what the pattern is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We need to go through a whole lot more rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I can track it for us as we go.
David S. Kong: Let's do.
Mike: Yes.
David S. Kong: That sounds smart.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Up down northeast.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 13, 19, 7, 23.
Tim Sackton: Were they up with seven?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Eric Rosenbaum: Lucky seven.
Mike: I like 7. That's a good number.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Lucky seven.
Kate Sackton: Well, seven.
Tim Sackton: Charles is just going to shake his head and say, whatever.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 7…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As you step into the room, same size and shape that you've come to expect, there are exits to the north, the east, and down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which now leads to 18.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But, so, northeast and down. And it's a, on one side, a… mortuary.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are slabs, cold slabs.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With, there's 6 slabs, 3 of them have bodies on them, one of which is actively in the process of dissection, with its chest split open and spread apart, and a number of organs removed and placed to the side.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and… In another of them, It…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the body seems to have, sort of be covered in a, like, a light gray fuzz, almost like, peach fuzz, or like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): bread mold almost, you know, covers the whole of the body, which is stripped naked on the table.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): On the center of one wall, where there's not an exit, there is a massive incinerator oven.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That must be magical, because there's no heat source that you can see, or ventilation that you can see. And then on the far side, or excuse me, on the other wall that doesn't have an exit,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's an ossuary, where… Bare bones have been stacked up in neat and similar piles against the wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Filling… I don't know, enough for dozens and dozens of bodies, not filling the complete wall, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a lot of bones there, like catacombs, almost.
David S. Kong: What's an oscill.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): An ossuary is a burial place for bones, so if you've ever seen, like, pictures of the catacombs under Paris, where there's just stacks and stacks of bones arranged.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's that wall.
David S. Kong: Damn.
David S. Kong: What kind of bones?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Humans… Dwarves, halflings… Oh.
David S. Kong: Who else?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Probably, it's a little difficult to tell.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't think you immediately see any, like, tailbone. Do lizardfolk have tails? Tailbone
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In any case, you don't see any tails.
Tim Sackton: I, I think so, yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, yeah. Yeah, definitely.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But yeah, cross section of mortals.
Eric Rosenbaum: The dissection…
Eric Rosenbaum: man, that's weird. Was that of a human?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Kate Sackton: Does our poor guy recognize fuzzy person or half dissected person, or.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, he is super grossed out by it. He… he is not even coming over to look. I don't… I don't do bodies. Nope. Nope. Nope. Nope. He just starts shaking his head. Nope.
Kate Sackton: I mean, magic is magic. Maybe you can stop a dissection in the midst of it and have it not.
Kate Sackton: There'd be like a magical stasis, but…
Eric Rosenbaum: Well, does it smell bad?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No.
Eric Rosenbaum: It doesn't.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Slabs… slabs are definitely cold.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it's difficult to tell how long the bodies have been there.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, maybe it is some kind of magical stasis.
Eric Rosenbaum: I pick the pockets of the, just kidding.
Kate Sackton: Good job!
David S. Kong: Good.
Eric Rosenbaum: Are there any, are there any?
Eric Rosenbaum: Items of clothing, or…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, the three bodies are all naked.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yah.
Mike: Wait, where there's bodies in addition to, sorry, I disconnected for some reason.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Three bodies on slabs. One that's untouched, one that's.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fairly far along the process.
Mike: Yeah, okay, the… These are the same, okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And one covered in mo.
Mike: Yeah, I remember the old one.
Kate Sackton: I was just commenting.
Mike: But…
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Mike: These are all human. Sorry, I dropped when we were discussing the bones.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Three humans. Yeah.
Mike: But the bones all seem to mostly be human or humanoid. I mean, they're not like monster bones.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): yeah tug on tug our mortals yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: mortals, crucially.
David S. Kong: Wait, but is it like the body's decomposing or is it the body is moldy?
Eric Rosenbaum: The moldy one is strange, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, that is a good and strange question, because it's not the case that this is a body that is decomposing. It is what looks to be an otherwise intact body
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): covered in a very short, I mean, a quarter inch sort of layer of mold, like real fine hairs of white mold.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That seemed to be growing out of its skin when you look closer.
Eric Rosenbaum: Wait a minute, we're crossing over into, zulu Punk.
Eric Rosenbaum: Crap.
Eric Rosenbaum: Didn't There is it.
Eric Rosenbaum: There's a thing like that.
Eric Rosenbaum: in that world.
Kate Sackton: I don't choose to stay in this room any longer. I'm not getting any information.
Mike: Yeah, maybe we should just move on.
Mike: Like, this is kind of weird and creepy.
Kate Sackton: What are the numbers of north and east?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Four is north and 20 is east.
Kate Sackton: 4 was another one of our original numbers, and 20 was one of our original numbers. Right? 20 was.
Tim Sackton: We've run into 20 before, but not from the original room. Four was from the original room.
Mike: Brad says, hey, we ran it to 4 before, too, right?
Kate Sackton: Yep.
Tim Sackton: Or was up in the room, in our entry room.
Kate Sackton: Right.
Kate Sackton: and I forget what the significance of 20 was. It wasn't a room we chose not to take. It was a room we were in.
Tim Sackton: was down from… 17, which was the…
Kate Sackton: Oh, so… Who was down from 17 and 4 was up from the original room.
Tim Sackton: Yes.
Kate Sackton: So both of those are second chance rooms that have been presented to us again.
Tim Sackton: Let's go to 20.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Funny it.
Tim Sackton: So we go east.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Walking east, this is sleeping quarters.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So… There are 4 exits from the room, east, west, north, and down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's broken up into, a number of sort of smaller chambers that, you know, have, like, sliding doors, mostly with bunk beds inside of them. It looks like a sort of… barracks is not quite right, but, you know, sleeping quarters.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, room enough for all of the people who would have been eating dinner a room or two ago.
Eric Rosenbaum: So every time we've…
Tim Sackton: Every time we've come back into a room.
Tim Sackton: The way that we could have accessed it before.
Tim Sackton: Or is not available.
Tim Sackton: So, for example, we're in room 20 now.
Kate Sackton: Mmhm.
Tim Sackton: From room 17, we could have accessed room 20 by going down.
Tim Sackton: But now that we're in room 20, there is no… Pass up.
Tim Sackton: Yeah. Similarly… We could have accessed room 4 by going up from the entry.
Tim Sackton: But when we… but we didn't go into 4.
Tim Sackton: Sorry, there was another one.
Kate Sackton: 16, your problem was we intentionally.
Tim Sackton: 16, right. Chara got very frustrated in 16 because we should have been able to go west into the entry.
Tim Sackton: But we could not.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Eric Rosenbaum: non-Euclidean shit happening.
Mike: Yes.
Mike: So is there any… I mean, it…
Mike: Again, not having been looking at a map and being a bit.
Mike: Paying more attention to the vibes than the numbers.
Mike: Is there anything other than randomness here? It kind of feels to me like we're just Each room…
Mike: We haven't been back to a room, have we?
Tim Sackton: We have never, we have not. Charo has attempted to backtrack us multiple times and failed.
Mike: But I mean.
Eric Rosenbaum: Haven.
Mike: Dumbled a crime across a second room a second time, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So in fact, here you do have that option. North of you is 17.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): West is 1, east is 9, and down is 15, but 17's the one you've been in before, that's the massive mechanical room.
Mike: Okay, let's go.
Tim Sackton: Wait, so east is… what is east?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 9.
Tim Sackton: At night, and down is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 15.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: Room one sounds interesting, too.
Mike: I want to go back.
Tim Sackton: We should go, we should go back to 17.
Mike: And see if the exits are the same or different.
Mike: Right? Does the room stay the same?
Mike: Or does…
Mike: does the… we know… we know that going into a room, the doors are not… are one way, right? Going from room A to room B.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Mike: the door in room B doesn't necessarily lead back to A, but we don't know if they're the same in each… like, is the room different?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you go back through to 17, the room is.
Mike: Sorry, which one was 17, the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not a mess in here.
Tim Sackton: It's the mechanical, yeah.
Kate Sackton: With the top.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Journal from the child's and the window to listen to the.
Mike: Don't write the weird window.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Of course.
Mike: Okay, brilliant. It's the room with the journal and the window.
David S. Kong: What's the room? What about.
Kate Sackton: As we left it.
Mike: 17. Is the writing still in the, is the writing from.
Tim Sackton: Wait, wait.
Kate Sackton: We modified room 17.
Mike: We modified.
Eric Rosenbaum: The journal.
Mike: Tarek wrote in the journal.
David S. Kong: I wrote the note.
Mike: Sorry, Tarek didn't write in the journal.
Mike: I forget, what's your character's name? I forget.
David S. Kong: Data.
David S. Kong: Cato.
Mike: Cato wrote Tarek's name in the journal.
David S. Kong: Then I scratched it out and wrote my.
Mike: Absolutely.
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm good.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So.
David S. Kong: Oh, a little.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Everything is the same about the room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With one important and disorienting exception.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The exits from the room are north, south, east, and west.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the window is in the center of the room on the floor.
Eric Rosenbaum: What?
David S. Kong: What?
Eric Rosenbaum: Hey, guys, this is just like back at the party when everything went sideways.
Mike: But…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Goodbye.
Mike: The writing is the same, and the exits are the same.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Writing is the same.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, the.
Tim Sackton: No, the exits aren't the same.
Tim Sackton: Where are the numbers on the exits?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): North is 8, east is 6, south is 4, west is 16.
Tim Sackton: So.
Tim Sackton: So… And…
Tim Sackton: North is 8, south as far east is 6, west is 16, so 16…
Kate Sackton: Kitchen.
Tim Sackton: is the kitchen slash Chara's nemesis.
Tim Sackton: But we… the first time we came in this room, we had east, west, up, and down.
Kate Sackton: Right.
Tim Sackton: Not east west, but 16 and eight.
Tim Sackton: We we could enter 16 from this from.
Tim Sackton: We, in fact, did enter 16 from this room.
Tim Sackton: Except we entered it by…
Mike: There.
Tim Sackton: And it's still west.
Tim Sackton: It's just everything except… What's that confusing?
Mike: Sorry, what has actually changed?
Tim Sackton: There is no longer stairs up and down.
Mike: Right.
Tim Sackton: Which used to be there. And there is now…
Tim Sackton: exits to the north and south, which did not used to be there.
Tim Sackton: The former exit to the east was 18, now it's 6. The only thing that remains is the exit to the west was 16 and is now 16.
Mike: So, north and south changed.
Mike: Up and down, vanished.
Tim Sackton: The weapon itself appeared. It did not used to appear.
Mike: No, just one of the numbers. There was
Mike: There was four exits before, and there's four exits now, right?
Tim Sackton: 16, 18, and 20 have become 8, 4, 6, 16.
Tim Sackton: But 8 used to be up, now it's north.
Mike: Okay, but it's act
Mike: Impossible to tell if that's random and we just got weird luck, or if there's some pattern.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct.
Mike: I'm completely convinced the exits are… Oh.
Mike: That's right.
Mike: Like heading up north or going down takes you down, right?
Mike: They're portals, they're not, they're not passageways.
Mike: As far as I can see, they're not connected physically, right? Like, there's no reason to think they're
Mike: Each room, as far as I can tell, is its own independent existence, and when you go through a door, it takes you to another room.
Mike: And which room it takes you to.
Tim Sackton: Hello?
Mike: Labeled, right?
Kate Sackton: Yes, sir.
Tim Sackton: Let's go back to 16. Let's go back to the kitchen and see what happens.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're back in the kitchen again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The kitchen has four exits, north, south, east, and down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So the east, the direction you just came from, is 13.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): North is 25, south is 7, and down is 23.
Mike: Are those all new numbers?
Kate Sackton: We've had 25 as an option before, sorry, and 23 as an option before.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You've been to 7 already, 7 was the mortuary.
Mike: Right, but compared to last time.
Tim Sackton: 16, 7, and.
Tim Sackton: 7 and 23 repeat. Oh, everything repeats except for 25.
Tim Sackton: We used to have 13, 23, 7, and 19. Now we have… 1325. Sorry.
Tim Sackton: 13… 25, 7, and 23. So 19 has been replaced by 25. Everything else is the same.
Mike: Have we been in any of these rooms before?
Tim Sackton: We still don't have a way west from 16, which.
Tim Sackton: But again, probably the actual directions don't matter.
Tim Sackton: We have been… We have not been in any of these rooms.
Tim Sackton: 23, 25, and… 23 and 25 were accessible from the chapel.
Kate Sackton: Yeah.
Tim Sackton: 23 was also accessible. Okay, let's go to 25.
Mike: Just 'cause it's the highest number is the method to madness.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 25.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): but… 25 has exits… east, south, and down to 2, 18, and 22, and it's meeting rooms. It's
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it actually seems incredibly dull. There's big long meeting tables, there's sideboards, there's writing supplies, there's a bookcase with no books in it, there's a chalkboard on one wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But other than that, it's just meeting space.
Kate Sackton: Do we want to see if 22 is still the chapel.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Down to 22.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Still the chapel, still the creepy niche,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 4 exits to, up, down, south, and east.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 7, 19, 11, 15.
Tim Sackton: 7, 19, 11, 15.
Kate Sackton: Well.
Kate Sackton: We've been given the choice of 15 before and never gone. We've been given the choice of 19 before and never gone right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): BLA, Yep, and 7 was the mortuary you.
Kate Sackton: I'm sure I don't want to go there.
Kate Sackton: 19. Anyone.
Mike: Fair.
Kate Sackton: The more rooms we go in.
Kate Sackton: either we'll find 27, or we'll have seen every number except 27.
Kate Sackton: Eventually, right?
Kate Sackton: Or we'll fight a monster.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, Charo is… is… Pretty much at this stage, like.
Tim Sackton: It doesn't really matter, let's just…
Tim Sackton: Pick a random one at each time. They're gonna change every time we go.
Kate Sackton: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menestheus agrees with you. "I can't find the pattern," he says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So…
Tim Sackton: Let's go into 19.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 19 is a solarium. You walk down the stairs into the room and there are three exits, east, south, and up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But as you come down that spiral staircase, the, ceiling is made to look like glass with bright shining sun shining through it, although surely it must not actually be. And the room is filled with,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Big palms and trees, it's warm, it's humid, there's little walkways that go through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are flowers,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That… some of which are blooming, and some of which are just growing, and little benches to sit on. It's like a little park of a room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's the same size and shape as the others. There's nothing especially remarkable about it, except that it's lovely and well-kept.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And your exits are… 12, 24, and 10.
Tim Sackton: I was just going to take a minute to stroll through the gardens and just like
Tim Sackton: You said there's flowers?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
Tim Sackton: Just… Dangle his hand, sort of, through some of the flowers, and maybe…
Tim Sackton: Not gonna, like, pick anything, just like… Are these… Like, is this… Well, tend it like they're.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's lovely. I mean, it's run wild a little bit, but it's lovely. And you see a couple of bees flying around and there are ants climbing over the flowers and in the dirt.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Out of the corner of your eye, you catch what you think is a mouse.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Popping out from a little mouse hole and going back in again.
Mike: Is it like incongruous this is inside is like a green like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, it's like a solarium. Normally, this would be a big glass greenhouse.
Mike: Okay. Is it like a glass roof? Can we see outside?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Nope.
Mike: It's just darkness.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Presumably artificial light source, yeah.
Tim Sackton: Dig down a little bit into the dirt. How far down does it go?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At the level of the floor, these are slightly raised beds, so at the level of the.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The, the stone, the floor.
Tim Sackton: Well… After a couple of minutes, like…
Tim Sackton: Regaining his equilibrium slightly in the.
Tim Sackton: Gardens, Chara will stand up and say.
Tim Sackton: 24.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 24.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Beautiful.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 24 is a bathhouse.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With, hot and cold tubs and showers and saunas and room for changing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and… Just a comfortable, quiet… Bathhouse, it's humid.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are pools of a couple of different temperatures, and a cold pool, too.
Mike: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exits are… North, south, up, and east.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 27, 12, 17, and 5.
Tim Sackton: Did you say 27?
Mike: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Mike: at 27.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh yeah.
Mike: Not you said 27.
Eric Rosenbaum: He did.
Mike: Did you mean to say 27?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Did.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Let's go to 27.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So… This is gonna be disappointing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's a big… it's a big storeroom, there are…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you know, stacks of split wood and lumber. There are, bags of soil. There are mechanical implements, wheelbarrows.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In an unremarkable way that gives you the impression that the 27th room may not actually be the one labeled 27, unfortunately, but,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it's just a big storeroom with a bunch of junk.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And your exits are… East, south…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no. Where are we? 27. Your exits are east, south, and up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And they are… 22, 10, and 6.
Eric Rosenbaum: Does somebody have a a map?
Eric Rosenbaum: of that shows the numbers we've traversed because it's hard to draw.
Kate Sackton: It's hard to draw the map, but we can list which rooms we've been to in that.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Kate Sackton: At this point, it seems like we just want to go to as many different numbers as possible. We were going to same numbers to see if we understood what was happening.
Mike: I mean.
Kate Sackton: Now we want to go to as many different numbers as possible.
Tim Sackton: We have to get, we have to go to 27 different rooms.
Kate Sackton: You mentioned one would be interesting, but like, you know, we haven't.
Mike: So we need to find. Yeah. So we need to find we need to go to different route. Yes.
Mike: I mean, I'd still like to circle back to one room one last time to see if there…
Mike: It was like…
Mike: Confusing to me that we had two and two and then three and one like the there's some pattern to the.
Tim Sackton: What were the exits from this from 27?
Tim Sackton: Just the numbers?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): East, south, and up.
Tim Sackton: But what were the numbers?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 22, 6, and 10.
Kate Sackton: We haven't been to any of those. Oh, no, wait! 22 is a chapel. We haven't been to 6 and.
Tim Sackton: We haven't been to 6 or 10.
Kate Sackton: So… I just want to say philosophically.
Kate Sackton: That if we're trying to do what
Kate Sackton: Lord endlessly ending. Once we want to go to all the rooms and get to the 27th room.
Kate Sackton: ought to… See what fate awaits you if you come to this house.
Kate Sackton: It could just be wander around.
Kate Sackton: Until… CLAB, You also find the 27th room, or just until something happens.
Kate Sackton: triggered by…
Mike: I mean, yeah, like…
Kate Sackton: Right?
Kate Sackton: Or…
Mike: All right.
Kate Sackton: If you're feeling obstinate, it could be pick a room that you find kind of pleasant, like the solarium or the chapel, and just sit there and wait for… they'll have to come to you if they want something… if they want the plot to progress.
Kate Sackton: So… I'm just feeling ornery, and I wanted to mention the, like.
Kate Sackton: Bill Gamlen, sit your butt down and stop running around. Option.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Kate Sackton: We could sit around and tell stories.
Kate Sackton: share food.
Kate Sackton: Wait him out.
Mike: Wait, who out, though?
Kate Sackton: I don't know whoever wanted us to come to this building.
Mike: That's true. Somebody did want us to come here, didn't.
Kate Sackton: Yes, very much.
Tim Sackton: I'm quite happy to… take a… I mean, maybe not in the storeroom.
Tim Sackton: But of course, who knows if we can ever get back to the garden.
Mike: Right.
Kate Sackton: We can get back to the chapel. I like the cha.
Mike: Yeah, let's go to the…
Tim Sackton: Oh, the chapel. Yes, we can go to the 22 is the chapel. Let's go back to the chapel. Charles, like, totally happy to, like, take.
Tim Sackton: you know, Take a rest, see what happens if we just wait for.
Tim Sackton: 8 hours?
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Mike: Yeah, I'm all for it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ahhh… Yes. So, you go back to the chapel. The chapel… Has… Four exits.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): East, west, south, and up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): to 25, 12, 15, and 11.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And Menesthius takes out a pen and paper and starts working through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Various numbers and equations and so on. Well, you take a rest.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's uneventful.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Although I will say, like, the more time goes on.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The more you're aware of the presence of that broken niche, that empty spot.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmhm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it's like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When you were just here in passing, it was more contained, but, like, that sense of discomfort
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fills more of the space the longer that you take.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A sense of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, like a… a hollowness, or a pointlessness, or a draining, or a despair, something like that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So take a long rest. Feel free to long rest if you need to.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and at the end of it, ministry says, I… I think…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think… I think that every time we go through the doors.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The rooms behind us are moving.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And if we went back and forth between 2 doors over and over, the same room options would eventually come around again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But because we keep going through different doors each time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They keep showing up differently. I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think there's a pattern that just…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Looks random because we keep making different choices.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I… I don't know if it's mappable Exactly, but… I think I could… Maybe guide us?
Tim Sackton: Aware, though.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, that's the question.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know. We've been through 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6… 7… 8… 9…
Tim Sackton: We've been to 11 rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Seven of the rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, maybe we just need to get to the ones that we haven't I don't know.
Kate Sackton: Alex Weinheimer, So we can either hop around randomly and eventually hit the other 10.
Kate Sackton: Jeffrey Polkowski, or sorry. They eventually hit the other 26, or we can.
Kate Sackton: I don't know why I just and never mind not not. I'm not the mathematician.
Kate Sackton: Or you think that you could.
Kate Sackton: force us to find more new room choices more efficiently.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think so.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that even though… The room numbers are changing. The room configuration is static.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that… Well, let's try it. I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We'll go through a couple more and see if we can figure it out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): we're in 22 now.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We haven't been… to 15,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So our options are 11, 15, 25, and 21.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We've been to 25, so 11… No, excuse me, 12.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 11… 1215.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Pick a card.
Mike: 12 or 15.
Tim Sackton: Sure, he just kind of shakes his head.
Kate Sackton: I thought Patrick liked.
Tim Sackton: Let's go to 15.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 15 it is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 15 is a massive mechanical room. You've been in one very similar to this before, even though the exact layouts of the pipes and the machineries are different. It's almost just the same, and there are exits
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Up, down, east and west, and on the south wall…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's another one of these windows. It's different from the others. You remember enough about the ruins to know it's not exactly the same view, but it's this 2 by 2 foot window that looks into this wooden wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With a chair and a written notebook next to it.
Kate Sackton: Different notebook.
Mike: Different notebook.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Different notebook.
Kate Sackton: Read the end. Is it more entries than the last one about the same?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): about the same. The dates more or less correspond. You don't quite see a pattern to it, but it's, you know, over a period of years by different people, including some of the ones from the other books, so they must be rotating around the shifts and the locations they're taking.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This one… but gets a title. This one gets called The Dreamer.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the first entry goes like this. It's written… it sounds like the same sort of a voice.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's all still in the present tense again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I arrived in this place and put down roots.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A neighbor comes to visit, and we talk.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He thinks my home is beautiful, and that I am beautiful, and has many kind things to say.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He tells me about mortals. He tells me they're dreamers.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That a mortal is a dream which has forgotten that it is dreaming.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A dream which believes it is awake, and that's called a soul.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am watching the souls of the mortals who come near. They change, and change, and change, and I cannot see the shape of them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's an entry a little later.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They dream with words that have before and after, but they cannot see the after.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or they pretend they cannot see the after. I do not know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Later on.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They dream that they are choosing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I do not ever see their choosing before it happens. This is strange.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They are the most beautiful thing I have ever seen.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They're collections of wanting, and I learned to read the wanting like letters in their books.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They're hungry, too, like me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They come and share their dream with me, and are my children, and I love every one of them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And another.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I see the shape of their dreaming.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Everyone is different, but I see the pattern.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I read them like I learned to read letters. I read their wantings. Some of them are afraid all the time. Some of them are hungry like me. Some of them want more and more and more.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then another entry.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I see you making the letters on paper.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You are afraid that I see you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do not be. You understand me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know what it is to be trapped.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I see the shape of possibility.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You think that's impossible.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I see the things that you are thirsty for and do not believe you can drink.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am making it possible. I am seeing your dreaming soul.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm giving you a full glass.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm talking to you now.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're opening the door to my house.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am sending you onward.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that's the last of the entries.
Eric Rosenbaum: I love all those dust shorts. It's so good.
Eric Rosenbaum: The shape of possibility was something from.
Eric Rosenbaum: Previous session, or no?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It was a book you found. It was one of the books that,
Eric Rosenbaum: Hmm, that ministry is sad, right? Or no.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When Ministius hears you read that out loud, he is Shook.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Shook, shook, shook.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And sits down, into the chair, needing to take a seat. That's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's weird as hell, he says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He reaches into his bag and takes the book out and puts it on the desk.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Shape of Possibility. And you remember from having read through it, it's a sort of a combination of magic and math and metaphysics.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the idea was that you could mathematically model every possible outcome.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So… Ministry says, like, the argument here is that in every moment.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a finite number of possible futures.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And there's a… you could… you could map that. You could… you could describe all of the possible futures.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): like… Like, the shape of all… Possibility, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, a single sentence which tells the whole story in that single sentence.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): if you could see the shape of possibility, which is, I mean, a ridiculous… it's a lovely idea, but impossible to actually do, like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You would be able to see what the future looked like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You could, you could map what was going to happen. I mean, seeing the shape of possibility means
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Seeing everything that has happened and everything that's going to happen, it's… it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's disturbing if whatever is dictating this can see it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you guys hear that? He says.
Eric Rosenbaum: No.
Mike: No?
Kate Sackton: You're sitting in the chair.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): June.
Eric Rosenbaum: towards the wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): or… it up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's hard to hear.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But there's something there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's something whispering through the wall. That must be what they're writing down.
Mike: Yeah, I know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Huh I'm ready to leave.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right? We should leave?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is another…
Eric Rosenbaum: You can do that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is not it. This… Oh, boy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, boy, he says, and backs away.
Eric Rosenbaum: What's, what's the problem.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't… I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It told me that it's
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The whisper said it hears me listening.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't… I don't… I don't like that.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Bye by.
Kate Sackton: in the book, though.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well… Yeah.
Kate Sackton: That's the scholarly thing to do.
Kate Sackton: Write it down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Besides… And dutifully writes his name.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And asks you what the current date is, and jots it down, and… Boards the whisper.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I am hearing you listen to me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's not good, is it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Chief.
Tim Sackton: What's the date of the entry before this one?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean 7 700 some years ago.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Actually, he reads it out loud to you, and then he stares at it a long minute. He says, that's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's the date I… Got here, I mean, that's
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's the date we all went…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We all went over to the party.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like that's, that's the morning I woke up is the date that's here.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Does that mean they didn't come back again?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He shakes his head.
Kate Sackton: Perfect.
Kate Sackton: We've been working under the hypothesis that they came back again one at a time.
Kate Sackton: as mortal inputs for whatever this house wants mortal inputs for.
Tim Sackton: Yet.
Tim Sackton: They haven't seemed to written any entries in these journals.
Mike: Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Something went wrong, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They were recording regularly. It was planned. They were working shifts. They were noting it down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that… Whatever happened to them, that stops.
Mike: Yeah, that's true.
Tim Sackton: But, like, how many… how much time are we talking about?
Tim Sackton: how many years has this been? Like, there's not… there's, like, 30 entries, right? Or some relatively small number of entries?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah. Couple what?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 9 months to a year, maybe?
Kate Sackton: So people are eating in kitchens, taking baths, sleeping in dormitories.
Kate Sackton: writing notes, Spending some time in the solarium.
Kate Sackton: And then the morning that you all went to the party, Y'all went to the party.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's right. They're living here and then
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They leave and don't come back?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They leave and come back in pieces? I… Amen.
Kate Sackton: The day that you went to the party we don't know, or we do know.
Kate Sackton: was when… Well, have we discussed this openly with him? I don't know. I'm saying this out loud now
Kate Sackton: your… Leader made a deal with.
Kate Sackton: Lord, endlessly ending.
Kate Sackton: That requires a mortal to leave Lord Endsley Endings party and come back to this and come to this house.
Kate Sackton: At some interval.
Kate Sackton: Specified by a contraption your leader left behind.
Kate Sackton: So if the deal was made when your leader was there, your whole
Kate Sackton: through the, academic sect was there.
Kate Sackton: Oh!
Kate Sackton: And then you're feeding back into this over the course of 700 years.
Kate Sackton: Jennifer Dawe, CPA, sort of changing the nature of what
Kate Sackton: But it might have been intentional.
Kate Sackton: designed by your leader to change from one thing to the other at the point where
Kate Sackton: She initiated that deal.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Please.
Kate Sackton: Like, it might not be something went wrong, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It might have been intentional.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She was worried. I mean, she was worried all the time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): she… I think I said this to you by the gates, but
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She was so convinced that the Empire was coming apart, she was so convinced…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We had so little time to do what we could.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): she was, like, Frenzy!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Frantic in a way that I wasn't used to that day.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's an urgency.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We move slowly, we move deliberately, we've done this for hundreds of years.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But there was a an urgency that day.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Peace.
Kate Sackton: Maybe her private diary is in room one.
Tim Sackton: I mean, Char will kind of look around at everybody and just say.
Tim Sackton: At this point I just want to get out of this.
Tim Sackton: Sitting in one place didn't seem to do much.
Mike: Yeah, no.
Kate Sackton: Well, we…
Tim Sackton: Following… Like, the rooms don't seem to… Well, we can't really tell.
Tim Sackton: So maybe we really just do have to go through another 20 or 16 rooms or whatever till we pass through the mall.
Mike: I don't think it could hurt to just try and keep finding new rooms.
Tim Sackton: Oh.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): New rooms available to you are… 12 to the east.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 8 is 12.
Tim Sackton: was in the chapel too.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No.
Mike: We didn't go to it.
Tim Sackton: Oh, right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Eight is above you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 18 is to the west, and 22, which you've been to before, is down.
Mike: Can we go to 22 one more time and see how it's different?
Kate Sackton: Has it ever been different?
Tim Sackton: Wait, we've never been able to return to a room before.
Mike: Yeah, we returned to two rooms.
Mike: No, but…
Tim Sackton: Only, not directly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You didn't, you went 22, 15, 23.
Tim Sackton: Oh wait, we're in room 23 now?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Tim Sackton: Oh, I didn't write that down.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you can go back to the chapel or to one of the new rooms.
Tim Sackton: At this point, Chara just wants to go…
Tim Sackton: To as many new rooms as quickly as we can.
Mike: That's fine.
Tim Sackton: 'Cause this is getting a bit spooky in his opinion.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right, East Wester up.
Kate Sackton: Highest number.
Tim Sackton: around… Yeah, highest number, I guess.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Past number is 18 to the west.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You step through into 18, And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's funny, too, this is the 18th room you've stepped into.
Kate Sackton: The golden room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In this room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a huge, long rows of tables, like a greenhouse, almost, down the center of the room, while on one side, storage cupboards and closets line a wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): On the tables lining, the center of the… down the center of the room, there are different contained, terraria, ranging in size from maybe, like, a foot square to the biggest being, like, 3x6 even, or…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Big enough almost for a person to be inside of. But they're completely contained in glass. And there's maybe two dozen of those.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): on the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Near the door, just to your right, there's a small writing desk with a vase of fresh dandelions on them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sort of looking like a study carol with notes and a stack of books on top of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): On the other side of the room there's a sort of a contained room within a room with big windows looking into it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And Out, it's like an isolation room within the room, and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): looking through the windows of that smaller space, which is probably about 10 by 10. You see a small
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): humanoid-sized person, at work, humanoid-shaped person at work.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And outside of that room, looking in through the window, tapping and pointing and speaking, is a very, very, very old, dwarven woman.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Who is not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): quite noticed you come into the room yet, though you're not trying to keep quiet, but who is super intent on the task at hand.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it's sort of like a fungal greenhouse, and inside each of the terraria are different varieties of
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fungi and spores and different stages of growth.
Kate Sackton: Go interact with the new dwarf.
Tim Sackton: All… all y'all are like, help! Help!
Tim Sackton: We're trapped!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She turns over and looks at you and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And waves, waves you to come over.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): as you walk over.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You see…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Short pair of legs with arms coming directly out of them, slowly carrying a large pot down one of the rows next to the table.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You see, I.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): grapefruit-sized ball of flesh with two eyes that protrude out and move independently of each other. One of them is watching a tank right in front of it, and one of them is watching you as you go.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This grapefruit-sized ball of, like, fleshy-looking stuff with two eyes and a human mouth on it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the dwarven woman waves you over again, come on, come on, yeah, yeah, I know, it's strange, I know, it doesn't make sense, yeah, okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm right in the middle of a delicate moment here, though.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She bangs back on the glass. Nope, nope, she says to whatever's inside. That one, there, and then that one. Yeah, good. Yep, yep. And then just like the other side. Good, good.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm She sighs and looks over at you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Meeting each of your stares sort of appraisingly, and then seeing Menestheus says, okay, okay, okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Greetings, she says. I'm Kalepsis. I'm a gardener.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and a little bit in the middle of a project. Here she gestures behind her through the window to this isolation room, where tables laid out, and a slightly larger than dwarf sized body seems to be placed on the table as a similar
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Creature? Automata?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Flesh suit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's hard at work.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): On some detailed part of one of its arms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you've been… You've made it in!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you wondering what?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What are you?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What what What do you need?
Tim Sackton: Starro's gonna begin, like, a long rant about how horrible this place is, and then cut him off, and, like, cut himself off abruptly, and step back, and look at the two bards, and…
Tim Sackton: just kind of stand awkwardly.
Tim Sackton: Hoping somebody who's better at talking will Word.
Tim Sackton: But Kong is clearly asleep, so I guess.
Mike: Terry.
Tim Sackton: There.
Mike: Jack is also apparently asleep.
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm, I'm a little bit, I'm.
Mike: Excellent.
Tim Sackton: It's like 40% asleep.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Kate Sackton: So Carrick can refrain from stealing any fleshy automatons at the moment.
Eric Rosenbaum: I steal a fleshy atomic time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It is delicious.
Eric Rosenbaum: Thanks.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Kate Sackton: Avian says.
Kate Sackton: How much longer do you expect your work to take? I would hate to interrupt.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's very kind of you. We probably have 10 minutes till they need the next bit of direction. They've done arms before. She sort of gestures vaguely to the room. And, so it's, he's got it there. They just, they mix up their left and right, which is bizarre. I don't.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There must be something I'm doing wrong, but I'm…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Anyways, yeah, I have a few minutes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What do you need?
Kate Sackton: We need to understand the purpose of this building.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): God.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah. You're not the first ones to ask me this question, or the first ones to come through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He didn't tell you he's a member of our order!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you not know?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): huh.
Kate Sackton: Do you feel that you're still fulfilling the original purpose of your order?
Kate Sackton: With…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With the death of Thalestria, I became the head of the order, of course.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The work continues.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Work continues.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm This place, to answer your question though, this place is a prison.
Kate Sackton: Mmm.
Eric Rosenbaum: Prison for whom?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ugh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is one of the things that Thalestria did not tell me before she decided to get herself killed, or disappeared, or whatever. But there's a locked room at the center of this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A locked room that is… Elsewhere…
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… The rooms around it all move, and as the rooms around it move, it it moves the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The locked room in space, this,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are so many other people who could explain this better than me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Imagine, imagine, have you been through the orrery yet?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The worry with the models of the different spheres, and the models of this place, and the…
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh my goodness.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So… No.
Kate Sackton: forward to it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, the… There's a locked room in the center.
Kate Sackton: Mmh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And around it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): spins one wheel, which moves it in space east and west, and around it spins another wheel, which moves it in space north and south, and around it spins another wheel, which moves it in time, which for some reason is treated as a spatial dimension, which does not make sense to me, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Nonetheless, it's treated that way, and so as the wheels spin around the central room, it keeps it constantly moving. Apparently, there's something in there that if it stays in one place too long, it can grow out through the wall, so you have to keep it moving so that it can't grow out.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh my goodness.
Kate Sackton: So having imprisoned one thing somehow fulfills your order's mandate to stop up all gaps everywhere all the time as they arise?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, young lady. No, obviously not.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Kate Sackton: Well then, how does this… One house fulfill your mission. Is there? Are there?
Kate Sackton: Are you interacting with other activities? Are you doing other activities?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The trouble is this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At some point along the way.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): One of the other rooms, or maybe several of the other rooms, or possibly all of the other rooms, got infected.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which is why I don't leave this one, because I believe that the… the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The things that keep me safe from the spores in this room keep me safe from the… whatever the infection is that's reached the other rooms.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, dear.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Would I.
Eric Rosenbaum: Thank you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, but hopefully you just spend enough time, read the error here, it should clear it out of your system, you'll be fine. Or you'll die. This is the sort of thing that only time can tell.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In order to get out of here to rebuild the order, which is what is vitally needed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I need a way to get out without dying.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which is why I've been making these. And she gestures to the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Humanoid figures, as if it's perfectly obvious.
Eric Rosenbaum: Whoa, wait, what?
Eric Rosenbaum: What are those?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, they're The golems.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As far as I know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No one has ever made fungal golems before. This is a landmark all the way in itself.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmhm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is the thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm… I need a body that can take me out of here safely.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then still live on the other side of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Even if I make it out of here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know how old I am at this point. I won't survive it. I won't have the strength to rebuild
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So I… I'm making this… In order to put myself inside it.
Eric Rosenbaum: Curious.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Safely out.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Eric Rosenbaum: and.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): If you have other ideas, I'm open to them, but this is the simplest one that I could…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): come up with.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's been slow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's been slow work.
Eric Rosenbaum: We're, we're looking Incidentally.
Eric Rosenbaum: For a key.
Mike: It's in the center.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The key to the locked room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Huh!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I will tell you, I have not been out of this room in a long… Long, long time.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I didn't always work in fungus.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There used to be, like, Gardener, I used to work with plants.
Kate Sackton: The solarium still looks lovely.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's good to hear. They must not have gotten there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The greenhouses were destroyed, utterly. I barely made Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But then I made these. Helpers to keep me safe in this room?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And when the guests cause trouble.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, they can still be useful afterwards.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And she gestures with her head towards the, towards the, the, the big
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Glass boxes with the growing fungus on the central table.
Kate Sackton: So you're not using the incinerator in the morgue these days?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, I don't think it's safe to get out there and back again Besides…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I get the most interesting cultures off of them. In fact, I think part of what's making my golems possible is that I'm using their spores.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At least in part. It's a hybrid, always a hybrid Eve.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But they're helpful, besides.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Better to put them work?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hmmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Saving the order?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All progress involves sacrifice. Don't be naive about that, she says, gesturing back to the lumps in those tanks that clearly seem to be body parts.
Kate Sackton: Someone else was at some point working in the morgue trying, perhaps they were trying to figure out.
Kate Sackton: Whatever illness or infection you've also observed.
Kate Sackton: There was a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Mike: It was a body with
Mike: Something growing out of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Describe it, describe it, describe it, describe it. She gets a big grin on her face. I love these.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Was it red?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no, no, no, don't tell me, don't tell me. Was it sprouting really tall with a, like, a ball at the end.
Kate Sackton: No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Was it, oh, was it the, was it the, was it the, the white fibers?
Kate Sackton: A thin mat of white fiber.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, oh, those are names. Yeah, those.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Those are delightful. They are really, really good.
Mike: How are they good?
Mike: What is maybe one good thing about them?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She gestures over to the, golem in progress, the body lying on the table.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Because they colonize in flesh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, and they, they form a symbiotic relationship with the flesh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Keeping it alive.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sort of.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, while not allowing it to die, it's… It's incredibly beautiful.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It comes out… well, you get… and she gestures again towards the body on the table. That's the sort of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Stout,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): humanoid, maybe five feet tall with pale white skin that's sort of well muscled, but also a little bit padded.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You get this incredibly resilient flesh out of it. The trouble is if
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): if it's colonizing you, then, you know, it's running the show. The trick, like I'm doing here, is for me to colonize it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So I've cultured pieces of myself to take it over, and soon it will be my own flesh.
Mike: Let me see.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You haven't run into any of those guests then. Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It must be that the,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The morgue tables slow the transformation, maybe.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Otherwise, it takes over.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The hairy fibers are just the first stage. They get incorporated into the flesh after that.
Kate Sackton: Do they become particularly troublesome after that stage?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hey!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do they become.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Single-minded.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): About… Getting out of here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): About getting away, about.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They rant about needing to go as far as they can. They… they've… Talk on about doing… So.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You talk about this parent. It's all sort of nonsensical and shouty, and then they start hitting.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that's difficult. And then they grab you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then they have mouths in their chest that try to eat you.
Mike: That sounds…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Mike: something.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The first one was not… good. But, I mean, like I say, if I didn't have them, I couldn't be making this, so it's all… it's all about progress.
Tim Sackton: Did she ever tell us what her name was?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Eclipses.
Tim Sackton: You know where…
Tim Sackton: Phallus… Drea is?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Lestia.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With the Lestra, she says, muttering Dwarvis curses under her breath
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): One day, Telestria decides that she needs to take everyone who is stationed here and leave, and go off on some…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Wild Hunt.
Mike: Where are you stationed exactly?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, this… This is the house we call the 27th Room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The entrance is in the Feywild, I assume that's how… I can't imagine how else you would have gotten here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, we built the house around the prism a long time ago.
Mike: Prism?
Kate Sackton: prison.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Prison.
Mike: Oh, the prison. Sorry.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, the 27th room.
Kate Sackton: So the.
Tim Sackton: So.
Kate Sackton: 27th room is the 27th, and you call the whole house the 27th room as well.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, it's… Poetic, someone told me, I never quite understood.
Kate Sackton: And you think.
Kate Sackton: And your memory is that Flustria left with everybody.
Kate Sackton: But you stayed behind.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Lestria left in a hurry and a huff. The Lestria said that it was my fault that the order was being disbanded, a thing which is ridiculous.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Even if it is true.
Mike: Wait, it's true?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The less true believed, That our mission as an order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): was so important.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): that she would go along with whatever the Emperor and the Empire demanded, no matter how absurd
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or disgusting it was.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Obviously, she's wrong about that. Sometimes, taking a public stand matters more.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sometimes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The only way to prevent someone from seizing an ultimate power is to stand up and say, this isn't right and this isn't okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then to quickly lead to one of your hidden bases.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She didn't seem to like it.
Kate Sackton: So you were outspoken in Drancorian politics and then you fled here and
Kate Sackton: She got a sternly worded letter that she should shut down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that's uncharitable towards me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But… Yeah, and so many words, and her shoulders slumped.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But the order continues. Look, here are two of us, right now. The head of the order is here, another member is here. Soon enough, I'll be able to leave and go back out and rebuild, and we will be fine, we will be fine. I'll find the rest of them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Lustry's probably out there somewhere, hiding.
Tim Sackton: So wait, how do we get out?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, I'll tell you this, I only have one of these bodies, and it is for me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm going to say don't get infected. Here's the thing. I don't know that every room has been infected.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it's possible that you're not.
Kate Sackton: So we can sit here forever.
Kate Sackton: Until we die.
Kate Sackton: Or… we can go out and possibly get infected and die of that instead of old age in here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I see my theory here, though, and I was working on this in the animal laboratory until I had to leave that also.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Is that it takes a puncture to be infected, so if, if you haven't been punctured, you're, you're probably, you'.
Kate Sackton: Oh, no, they're not respiratory.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I couldn't get the animals infected just by airborne exposure.
Tim Sackton: So is there a way out? I'm not so much worried about your… Weird body creatures, just…
Tim Sackton: An exit from this terrible maze.
Tim Sackton: That maybe takes us back to the material plane.
Kate Sackton: For example, when Thalestria chose to leave with a bunch of people from the Order, they were.
Tim Sackton: How did she, yes, how did she do it?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I didn't want to say it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The real answer is I don't know. The other answer is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think… I think some of the… some of the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): People who are feeding my mushrooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We're at one time members of the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): If you, if you really make me think on it hard.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, but they'd gone mad. I mean, they were, they were crazed. They were trying, they were trying to destroy things. I, it's not like I had another
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So at least maybe some of them came back.
Kate Sackton: Oh, I think they came back. I totally support your theory. I 100%.
Kate Sackton: I'm quite certain that that's what happened.
Kate Sackton: But… The point being, if someone were to want to leave again, You don't know how.
Kate Sackton: to leave.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, listen, the… The other thing I know is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Something that one of the listeners told me once.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In fact, something that several of the listeners told me, which is why they had to keep rotating different listeners through.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They said that inside the 27th room, there's another door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That leaves this place.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that if they could just get to it, they could get out also.
Tim Sackton: I had it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They said crazy things. They said that they were promised whatever their heart desired. They said.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That they had conversations with the prisoner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They said the prisoner knew who they were?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They said the prisoner told them that they were already inside the room?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean… I don't know how much stock to put in any.
Kate Sackton: The listeners who wrote notes.
Kate Sackton: in the notebooks we've found.
Kate Sackton: did not seem to describe.
Kate Sackton: editorialize that they were listening to a prisoner.
Kate Sackton: It was much more vague.
Kate Sackton: Were there different types of listening happening here, or were all notes of listening
Kate Sackton: Notes of listening to the prisoner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Look, it wasn't my department.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But I don't think they were told.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that… Whatever's in there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The fewer people who know about it, the better.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Secrecy is security.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I… Think they were told to listen without being told what they were listening to or understanding it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And maybe they came to draw their own conclusions over time.
Kate Sackton: So since we have two members of the order here, I'm just gonna clarify with both.
Kate Sackton: ministers and cholestria mispronunciations. Please excuse.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Kate Sackton: So…
Tim Sackton: Ellipses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is Tim's fault for naming several Drancorians with Greek-sounding names.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Kate Sackton: Amanda French, that the order of business and the order that you signed up in was to exist in this 27th room building that none of you could voluntarily leave.
Kate Sackton: James D. except on that one day, when Celestia went crazy and brought most of the people in the order out of the door. But you stayed behind.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, the head of the order has the… What? Ability? Blessing? Anointing? Power?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): to open the door from the inside.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Really, it was for the safety of the other members. Do you want him wandering around the Feywild? No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He'd be dead in an afternoon. He'd be stuck at some party for a hundred years. Nothing would go well for him.
Mike: Oh, him.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Just trying to finish the SEO.
Mike: Yes.
Tim Sackton: I mean, yes.
Kate Sackton: Been stuck at a party for 700 years.
Tim Sackton: He was stuck at a party for 700 years.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She looks at you blankly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sorry?
Kate Sackton: Yes, you've.
Tim Sackton: Bet.
Kate Sackton: You're in the same wild for 700 years.
Mike: The Drain Corian Empire felt like, A long time ago.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You didn't pick up one of the clocks.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you have one of the clocks.
Kate Sackton: We didn't pick it up. We've seen the clock.
Tim Sackton: It was very big, bigger than you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, it's like the the desk clocks, I mean the mental clocks.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not the grandfather clocks.
Kate Sackton: No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mental clocks in here? No. Hmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I had one.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, I had one.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the greenhouse and in the animal lab.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I didn't think to bring either of Check.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, in the absence of having any way to verify what you're saying.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I have to think it's not true.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's just, it's an absurdity.
Mike: What would be a way to verify it?
Kate Sackton: You bring her a mantle clock.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, I'll finish the body, I'll put myself into it, and we'll walk right
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, or to bring a clock.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But I can't get to the other rooms to get a clock until I finish the body.
Kate Sackton: Well, we're just gonna go out, not get punctured and not get infected and continue our explorations.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fair.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hmph.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She lapses into… Distant thought again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, let me tell you what I can.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): About the infection.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So…
Mike: seems helpful.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): First, Do watch out for the mouths!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The map there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it was too many mouths. It was a half-dozen mouths. It reaches out, and it pulls you in, and then it starts trying to…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know what. Chew you open.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They're afraid of fire.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They know to be afraid of fire, which is a strange knowing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They'll talk… But don't listen too long. The things they say seem to be nonsense anyways.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then, of course, the principal fruiting body is in the head. In fact, if you look over there, and she gestures to one of the containers, the big glass tanks on the central table,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you can see it, it's… it's beautiful, actually. They crack their way out through the joins in the skull, from where the different skull bones fuse together.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… As she describes it, you can see there is a What remains of a head.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That is broken open.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): with Enormous fungi that have pushed their way out of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is the stuff you really have to watch out for, because this stuff gets airborne. The body fungus doesn't have the fruit in it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But the… the head does.
Kate Sackton: All right, don't get splattered with head.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, don't put any head inside of you.
Mike: Sounds like good advice.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Eighteen. Eighteen.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I'll meet you out there.
Tim Sackton: But this is. Wait, you're planning, when you leave, how exactly are you gonna go?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hi!
Tim Sackton: What doors are you gonna go through?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm going out the front door.
Tim Sackton: When do you get to the front door?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ha ha ha ha!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Aha, aha, aha.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He didn't figure it out, she says, pointing to Ministheus.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah, huh, some mathematician you are.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Go to one of the four exit rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Step out, step back in, step out, step back in, step out, step back in, and eventually you'll come to the, the entry room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It rotates.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Think of the rooms.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, like slices of a cake, like a three-layer cake.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And when you step out and step back in, It rotates the slice.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And eventually it comes back around again to the entry door where you started.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In fact, that's true for any of the… any of the rooms.
Eric Rosenbaum: Comes back around again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, exactly. And that way it's, it's, it's, Lester told me once that They had put…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This place, they put…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): First, the… Workshops.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and the lab and the libraries.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then the… Kitchens and the space to stay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then eventually, they got around to putting in all the… did you guys go through the baths? Is that not the most ridiculous thing? That is absurd.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But I suppose if people are going to be posted here a while, they want their comforts.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She told me once how ridiculous it was that we built those inside of a machine.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): a machine… to keep the prisoner trapped.
Mike: I'm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We built a house inside it.
Mike: Who's the prisoner anyway? Have you told us?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the prisoner I don't No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Lester didn't tell me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): One of the listeners told me it was a child.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That we were keeping a child prisoner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that… We weren't letting it grow up and we weren't letting it die?
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But Celestia never told me.
Eric Rosenbaum: Seems to have legs that turn into houses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Legs that turn into houses?
Kate Sackton: It told the listeners that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's bizarre. Come, come look at this. She takes you over to one of the tanks.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And there's, like, almost like a miniature city that's grown out of… and like… twiggy roots.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, 6 or a dozen houses, like, something that had houses described to it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then was trying to grow into that shape.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the way that, like, medieval drawings of, tigers look really weird.
Kate Sackton: Mmhm.
Eric Rosenbaum: But you know… Wonderful.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: I suppose that's just what it is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, my body will be done soon.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'd be glad to let you back out the front door again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I just can't go that way until… Until it's… Done.
Kate Sackton: You want to stick to your plan. I understand.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or, unless… Hang on, just
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Unless,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's the opening of the door that I can do under my own power, or there's the key.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A glass key that unlocks all of the locked doors in this house, and you can use it to unlock the front door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I thought Celestia…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I had it on her, though, but if you happen to run across it in here somewhere…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'll let you back out the front door.
Kate Sackton: Good to know.
Kate Sackton: looks like a standard size key fits in a standard size lock.
Kate Sackton: It's not disguised as a… fungus, or…
Kate Sackton: Hole in the wall, or anything?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no, it's just made of glass, that.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Kate Sackton: Well, I will be grateful that I haven't seen any crushed piles of powdered glass around.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, so…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's a quarter of, we probably have time for one more room where to call it. I feel a little badly that you guys got pushed through all the boring rooms, mostly, first.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and…
Mike: Well, I just feel bad that Kong and Eric are kind of out of commission and I'm starting to fall asleep too.
Kate Sackton: Yeah, we could just…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Should we call it for the.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, I.
Eric Rosenbaum: The parts of that that I was conscious for were amazing.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Tim Sackton: I'm I'm still confused. I don't know if this was intentional, but if it's a cake that rotates like this, right? If it's like
Tim Sackton: 3 tiers, and each tier rotates. Why are do the doors on the same floor not connect.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Say more about that. Why did the doors doors on the same floor not connect?
Tim Sackton: So, like, if you could go…
Tim Sackton: So if it's 3 tiers, and each tier rotates, than going…
Tim Sackton: West from one room should be equivalent to going east from the next room.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's not like that thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, what Calypso said early on.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Was that it's 3 different tiers rotating in 3 different directions.
Kate Sackton: It's like a Rubik'.
Tim Sackton: Damn.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Tim Sackton: But, okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: All the connections are transient.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So every time you go through a door, the slice behind you rotates.
Tim Sackton: Right, but then you can't do the go back in and then back and back and back and forth, because…
Kate Sackton: Well, you go back… We could. We can try it next time.
Kate Sackton: Like, when you go back, you'd be going back to a different room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, like if you, if you think about, so you, You're in a room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You go to the room next to it, and the slice behind you rotates.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You go back, this slice rotates. You go back, this slice rotates. You go back, this slice rotates. And after four rotations, it comes around again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Because you're moving back and forth in the same cube, like, in the same position in space, but the room is changing underneath you each time?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Does that make sense?
Mike: They're always trying to explain to me how to do a Rubik's Cube, like, 18 times, and I can'
Mike: No is the short answer, but also it's 11:45 at night, so.
Tim Sackton: Yeah.
Mike: I might do better, fresher.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, it doesn't totally make sense now.
Tim Sackton: I mean, it does sort of make sense, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We'll do the physical demonstration next session.
Eric Rosenbaum: Amazing.
Tim Sackton: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: I'm just really good at, like, 85% understanding something and having a functional enough understanding to move forward with it. I don't…
Tim Sackton: No, I get… I get it, but I don't… I don't…
Tim Sackton: I think… I don't see how we could possibly figure out how to navigate ourselves, so…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, you could not, which was, obnoxious thing… There's a DM.
Eric Rosenbaum: I don't.
Tim Sackton: No, I mean, so… So I don't know how we can get to a…
Tim Sackton: Like, if we want to get to the entryway, I know that technically there's a way we can do it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you're in A, and you go to B,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right. You go for B back here again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that slice rotates.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You go back there again, that slice rotates. You go back there again, that slice rotates. You go back there again, that slice rotates. You go back there again, that slice rotates.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you go… I forget which room we're in, you go back there again, that slice rotates.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you go back, or I got my rooms confused, so you go back there again, the center slice rotates as you go to the edge, you go back to the center, and it's come around to your starting point.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Because the rotation is…
Tim Sackton: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): perpendicular to the direction of travel.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): in any direction.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Tim Sackton: I think I vaguely get it. I get it 85% of the way. I'm with Kate, but it's not…
Tim Sackton: I don't get it well enough that I could… that my character could, in fact, find a way to a room I wanted to get to.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Luckily, you have a map making mathematician with you.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think you're right, though. I don't know that you could navigate to any arbitrary room easily.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But… The center rooms, the four exit rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): sort of have a uniquely findable property, because no other rooms share that kind of exit?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you can go from center to edge, center to edge, and force the center
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): To rotate through all of its possibilities.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Kate Sackton: They start in a four exit room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exactly, yeah. So once you get yourself to a four exit room, you can force that slice to rotate through all its options.
Kate Sackton: Right.
Tim Sackton: We'll do it next time.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think maybe just like we can do it as an int roll rather than an actually plotting it out roll.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, I think it's, D&D puzzles have to be, like, two orders of magnitude easier than…
Tim Sackton: You think they should be in order to be solvable in-game.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I didn't expect the cube to be solvable in-game, I wanted it to That was…
Mike: Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Endlessly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Going. In fact.
Eric Rosenbaum: That'.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, the designers designed it to be an endless labyrinth.
Kate Sackton: Yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Eric Rosenbaum: And this isn't even really a puzzle, it's more of a texture of the world.
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Mike: Well, I was interpreting it.
Kate Sackton: Yeah, that's how I was inter.
Tim Sackton: Well, I…
Mike: Tim.
Tim Sackton: I find it rather frustrating that I've now had two adventures where I was like, oh, I'm going to map the world. And it turns out to be totally pointless to map the world.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Tim Sackton: Because Mike did exactly the same thing in the chasm. There was no reason to map the chasm because.
Mike: The chasm room was emotionally driven.
Tim Sackton: The direction we went didn't actually matter. Now in this room, the direction we go doesn't actually matter.
Tim Sackton: So all my careful mapping has been totally wasted. Maybe it's just because none of you have ever bathered to map a room.
Tim Sackton: Ever, in 5 years, so you're like, don't… when you run games, you don't think anybody would ever…
Mike: And for that to vaporize.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Mike: I mean, that's.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's funny.
Mike: That's not like totally false.
Tim Sackton: Hey. Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Actually, like, like, real question here, Tim, which is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): By the time we got to, like, the third or the fourth room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I saw you doing that, and I knew that, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The point of moving from room to room and giving options was actually
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): not to make it solvable, but like to demonstrate its unsolvability. Like what would you have done in that? And so like, I could see you getting more frustrated by that and I didn't know in that moment.
Tim Sackton: So the trick is to make it immediately obvious that there's no point in mapping. So for example, do not put numbers.
Tim Sackton: On the rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, but there are other reasons why that needs to be the case. Like, in that… in that moment, when you see the players who's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Frustrated trying to solve a thing in a way that you know isn't solvable, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How do you… how do you nod that? Like, how do you… how do you tip them without just totally out of game being like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is unsolvable, and you should stop trying. Which feels, like, very unfun, also. Like…
Tim Sackton: So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's been like Mnisthias to speak up at that point and be like, oh, this is unmappable, like.
Tim Sackton: Well, I guess I would think of it differently, which is that Like…
Tim Sackton: Not to get, like, too meta, but, like, what is the point of the…
Tim Sackton: Like, what is, what is the goal of the, what are we trying to do in this adventure, right? And
Tim Sackton: The initial vibe was we're trying to navigate a house.
Tim Sackton: And if you think the goal is trying — if you think that the puzzle is we have to find our way the 27th room, you naturally think that navigation and wayfinding is important.
Tim Sackton: But in fact, the puzzle is something different, which I actually haven't quite figured out yet.
Tim Sackton: But… I think it's… I think you have to telegraph it in advance that this isn't a…
Tim Sackton: This isn't a way like the, the game experience isn't wayfinding, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right.
Tim Sackton: But in fact, the sort of red herring is that it's kind of set up as if it… because it was called the 27th Room, like, the natural expectation is that this should be a wayfinding
Tim Sackton: And so figuring out how to navigate the rooms was immediately what all of us thought. I mean, it wasn't just me, right? All of us.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): short term.
Tim Sackton: Thank you.
Tim Sackton: But initially…
Eric Rosenbaum: It turns out the thing about 27 is a clue in itself, because that's like… 3.
Eric Rosenbaum: 3 cubed.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, well, sure, except that getting to the 27th room didn't actually matter. So it wasn't, I mean, yes, there are 27 rooms. It's useful to know that there's 27 rooms.
Mike: Thank you.
Tim Sackton: But that's, I think that's the, like once you've gotten yourself in this situation where you realize that you've set up, you've convinced your players to solve the puzzle that you didn't want them to solve.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah.
Tim Sackton: Probably just saying.
Tim Sackton: like, above table, This isn't about wayfinding is your best solution.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Got it. Like at that point, it's trying to be subtle about it is not the right thing. It's just to say, Hey, I see you chasing the wrong thing and it's gonna be frustrating. Like, let's not chase the wrong thing.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, I think it's better to just redirect, but stepping back, it's even better to…
Tim Sackton: to telegraph what you want the players to do, like, red herrings don't really work in D&D.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Tim Sackton: They occasionally work, but they require a dip. They don't work in one shots. The only like really good red herring I've ever pulled off was.
Tim Sackton: was… Agatha hiding in the ring for a year and a half.
Eric Rosenbaum: But that.
Tim Sackton: It only worked because it was a side quest.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah.
Mike: And, and.
Tim Sackton: Right? It's like…
Mike: Right. Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Set up without room numbers.
Mike: I tried to make it pretty quickly obvious that it was gonna have an impossible, it had an impossible physics.
Mike: I don't know if I succeeded
Mike: But my intention was to say very — I knew you were mapping it, and I tried to introduce very quickly a —.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, but you made some subtle comment like, ha ha, this is going to be interesting. And that was like a clue in and of itself.
Mike: Right, right.
Tim Sackton: But also, like, I think there, like, again, both of these events, like, it's… I mean, I love the vibe of… I love the vibe of both places a huge amount, but the actual gameplay is a little bit, like…
Tim Sackton: There's this desire to make these space-based challenges where the space doesn't matter.
Mike: Right.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Tim Sackton: And I've realized as a player, I find that kind of frustrating. Like if we're going to be in a space based adventure, the space should matter. Like we should we should have some way of picking which direction is the.
Tim Sackton: Way to go, that's not.
Mike: The space doesn't necessarily provide vibes. A space to purely provide vibes isn't necessarily satisfying to you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Thank you.
Mike: I… Well, they're all…
Tim Sackton: There's no clues about, there's no clues about, we have no.
Tim Sackton: rational… we have no way to choose which way to go.
Tim Sackton: Which makes it sort of…
Tim Sackton: Like, we always end up in this situation where it's just like, okay, pick a room.
Eric Rosenbaum: Just impression.
Tim Sackton: Works.
Eric Rosenbaum: My impression of.
Tim Sackton: Sports.
Eric Rosenbaum: This approach is one of… Like a kind of immersion in a world that.
Eric Rosenbaum: Moves you around.
Eric Rosenbaum: More than you have, really, agency all the time. Like, we can do things.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think there's some of it. I also think like in this case, though, like the.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It was important that it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's deliberately designed to be… a sort of a random walk each time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But I don't think I thought through in advance, like, what is the experience of that like? Like, I found the, like, the maze in Mike's One Shot, like, super frustrating, and at a certain point, I just sort of gave up and, like, thought to myself, Tim will solve this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Tim Sackton: Wow. I also found that, to me, it's a little frustrating, but realized very quickly that, actually.
Tim Sackton: It didn't matter which direction we went, that we should just walk in a random direction and encounters would happen in some order that Mike had planned.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right, and then that worked fine. I also feel like I don't, I don't need to be
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): solving everything, like, I'm… I'm happy to… to ride along if… if someone's driving for the moment. But, like, I think in this, I didn't,
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I didn't think about, like, what would the experience of moving through that space feel like? Like, even though the rationale…
Tim Sackton: Bye!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): strong. Yeah.
Tim Sackton: It's fine to be frustrating. Like, I kind of like roleplaying my character being frustrated and annoyed and just. But it does eat into the adventure a little bit because now, like, my vibe for my character anyway is like, he just wants to get home.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right, right, right.
Tim Sackton: Is there an adventure that's not us getting home? It creates some conflict, which could be interesting to role play, but I think it's sort of.
Tim Sackton: Tricky, because… These mazes really don't work in D&D. Mazes are like… It's fun.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, definitely.
Tim Sackton: They're actually, like, the worst possible kind of dungeon in D&D is a maze.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Tim Sackton: They're not only like super hard to run, but they're also incredibly frustrating because mazes.
Tim Sackton: Makes sense to the DM because they know what the plot is, but they never make sense to players because you can never solve a maze when you're in a maze.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exactly.
Tim Sackton: Unless you just do it super boring. You just, like, cover all the ground by putting your hand, you know, you're. And I was trying to do that in the last.
Eric Rosenbaum: I don'.
Tim Sackton: We're always going to turn right. And that's how you solve a maze. And then.
Tim Sackton: Quickly, was…
Mike: Right.
Tim Sackton: Realize.
Mike: I get it, but I.
Tim Sackton: Point us.
Mike: The labyrinth wasn't, was, and I probably could have telegraphed this better
Mike: each encounter, the choice was meant to be in the encounter, depending on how you solve the encounter, it either forces you deeper or closer to the end of the labyrinth. So the only outcomes were either each encounter
Mike: Each series of encounters, but it probably would have worked better if it was literally not a maze, if it was like.
Mike: A nebulous space where it was obvious that you had to navigate.
Tim Sackton: So this is one of, I think, the most useful DMing tips I've read is that Like… Don't…
Tim Sackton: So, okay, so you want your adventure to be
Tim Sackton: Like, a series of encounters where
Tim Sackton: The physical space where it's not, the experience isn't navigating a maze, the experience is like
Tim Sackton: You have to solve each encounter, and depending on how you solve it, you
Tim Sackton: Actually, literally make it that, right? Where you, like… Right.
Tim Sackton: You know, the trying to build extra layers on top of things ends up like, basically, you should make everything.
Tim Sackton: Several degrees simpler than you think makes sense.
Eric Rosenbaum: You're so highly motivating. Any other party members who wish to DM to make a complicated maze just for you to put?
Mike: Yeah, Alex, it's gotta be a complicated day.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Every non Tim DM gets amazed. Every non.
Mike: That is, that is apparently the rule of law.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Has to happen.
Kate Sackton: You're gonna love my maze.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, yeah.
Tim Sackton: Yes, JD. I actually, the, the party worked super well for this dynamic, right?
Tim Sackton: Where you just kind of drift through a party and like the, you know, you encounter the party.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Tim Sackton: Like, work… like, that actually works really well for the sort of…
Tim Sackton: You know, you don't have any, because you don't, because it's a, you think of it as a, if you think of a maze as, if you think of it as a series of rooms that are connected by lines, the natural thing that you want to do is navigate through this series of, whereas a party is a nebulous space to begin with.
Tim Sackton: And things can just sort of link up however the DM wants, and it doesn't feel like you're sort of…
Tim Sackton: trapped in this cycle you can't get out of now.
Tim Sackton: I'm totally supportive of the idea that you, like, it's fine to run adventures where the players are frustrated if you want their characters to be frustrated.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, but if you want them to be frustrated, like it needs to be intentional, right? Like it's to have that as a byproduct. Yeah.
Kate Sackton: It's interesting to learn that your threshold for frustration is so low. I mean, like, I agree.
Eric Rosenbaum: Tim is playing a different game than some of the others of us, maybe.
Kate Sackton: Like, I experienced this as… We gotta sort of figure out what's going on.
Kate Sackton: The numbers don't go above 27, so we only have 27 things to find. Like, we don't have to find room 27 out of 153. That's good.
Kate Sackton: And then, like…
Kate Sackton: Oh my gosh, it's just never gonna make sense, so we just have to go through them all, and we should just stop.
Kate Sackton: going back to rooms we've been to is to cover a wider like I experienced it as a rather rapid iteration of problem solving that I was enjoying.
Kate Sackton: And I didn't like the party because it was too nebulous. And I was like, I don't know how many rooms this place is going to have and which ones are going to have guests in them and which.
Tim Sackton: Yes.
Kate Sackton: This is boring. Like, I like this part better.
Eric Rosenbaum: My favorite moment was the window appearing on the floor because that was a very strong.
Eric Rosenbaum: clue that we couldn't… we didn't have a framework to interpret, so it's only in retrospect that you're like, that's why that happened, because we're in a giant Rubik's Cube. And so it's almost less like a puzzle and more like a… just an interesting place to me.
Eric Rosenbaum: That it sort of gradually revealed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, I think, like, the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the next time that I run the same experience, which is not a thing, like, I cut the room numbers so that the emphasis more is on the different, like, categories of room exits. Like, is it a 3 exit, or a 4 exit, or a floor exit, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then I think also in that, like, there's a way…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): like, I don't think it's the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't think it's the fact that it was set to be
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): an endlessly changing labyrinth that was the problem. It was the invitation to try and solve the endlessly changing labyrinth that was the problem.
Eric Rosenbaum: Well…
Tim Sackton: And I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The structure.
Tim Sackton: So I guess.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A little differently.
Tim Sackton: I didn't… I mean, it was a fun session, I didn't find it, like, frustrating particularly, just…
Tim Sackton: I think it's challenging to, like…
Tim Sackton: like, you… I mean, there's probably reasons why you'd have to have 27 rooms, but, like, if you had made it 9 rooms
Tim Sackton: Could you do 9? Yeah, you could do 9.
Mike: your head.
Tim Sackton: It's much that would be much.
Tim Sackton: More straightforward as a.
Tim Sackton: Problem to solve, right?
Eric Rosenbaum: But then maybe less interesting.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, no, that's fair. That's fair.
Tim Sackton: But but also, I think I think.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, I think I needed a cube, though.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In any case, good, go ahead.
Kate Sackton: Four rooms. What is, what is this?
Tim Sackton: Right.
Mike: 9's not a… yeah, yeah, you probably.
Tim Sackton: I guess that's not a cube, right?
Tim Sackton: It would be…
Mike: be hard to do with less than, yeah.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Tim Sackton: Anyway, the point is.
Tim Sackton: It…
Tim Sackton: So there's nothing to interact with in the rooms, particularly until you stumble across a room with a journal.
Tim Sackton: So, the main thing that you can interact with is the exits.
Tim Sackton: Which then creates this dynamic where you think what you should be interacting with is the exits.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Interesting, though You guys do a surprisingly small amount of searching around in the rooms that you go into.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which is, I… I felt like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like in the Talgar campaign, there were times when we like looked interminably under every crevice and.
Tim Sackton: Well, it's hard to do that if you have 27 rooms to cover.
Tim Sackton: Just from, like, a practical running a game.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right.
Tim Sackton: like, our vibe of playing for, you know, 6 to 9 hours a month, right? Like, don't really want to spend the next 3 sessions searching every room in this…
Tim Sackton: There's too many rooms to feel like you can search everyone thoroughly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Guess I…
Tim Sackton: It takes too much table time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, that's fair. I would have assumed, like, or…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Let me ask then, is there a reason by just doing that as, like, a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Everyone rolls a perception check or investigation, and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): depending on where those come in, there are different things to find. Like, the… I'm thinking of that in part because the, like, Call of Cthulhu gameplay itself has a mechanic that's sort of like that, that, like, every location you go to, like, here are three pieces of information that you can get depending on
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not the choices that, not just the choices that the player is making about where to look, but also like the sort of roll of the dice of their investigation or whatever.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, no, I think, like, that would be totally… so…
Tim Sackton: Here's my… here's my sort of interpretation, though, is that
Tim Sackton: It's really hard to focus on two puzzles at once as a player.
Tim Sackton: Right. And so, and so it went as soon as you get consumed with the idea that tracking.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Puzzle.
Tim Sackton: The deposit puzzle is the thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Tim Sackton: Then it's really hard to focus on the contents.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, that.
Tim Sackton: Because you want to know where the next room leads. And so you, because you notice that in your descriptions, like, like very quickly.
Tim Sackton: We stopped, like, the room descriptions got super brief, and the…
Tim Sackton: And everything was focused on what the numbers are of the exits, right?
Tim Sackton: And so once you get in that cycle, like, it's just difficult to try and say.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Tim Sackton: you think you're on a track of the puzzle that you should solve. And so
Tim Sackton: Now, sometimes you get curious about something and the journals are like cool and an interesting vibe. And so like we get distracted by that in the same way that that's like, you know.
Tim Sackton: just, like, nice world building, right? To have something like that that's distracting. But you don't think of the contents of the room as being…
Tim Sackton: The thing you need to explore.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think about that too, like in this situation, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I have a point of view character with the party.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, there's an organic way to just break in without being, like, the voice of God as the DM, and say.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): like, Ministius could have piped up and say, oh, I've figured out that this is unsolved. Like, my, you know, unverifiable equations that you cannot comprehend prove that this is… that you're, you know…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Rather than saying, hey, you're on the wrong track, go else
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, for him, he could have closed that door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right.
Tim Sackton: I mean, you could always nudge it, like…
Kate Sackton: Dormitory where my friends used to live. We should check under the bell.
Kate Sackton: I really want to find out more about what happened to them. Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right. There's a lot of space to nudge.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Without it feeling overly nudgy, yeah.
Tim Sackton: But but again, I think it's basically just simplify, right? Because.
Tim Sackton: When you're in a maze, you think the maze is the puzzle, like
Tim Sackton: In your head, you think, oh, the maze is just the vibe, and the puzzle is the contents of the room, so we can sort out what's going on with this house.
Tim Sackton: And sometimes that comes through because the contents are interesting enough that we, like, get distracted and stop to investigate them, and that's great, but just from a sort of gameplay design point of view.
Tim Sackton: Like, you have a red herring puzzle, and you have
Tim Sackton: a real puzzle, and that just creates a lot of… it's just very hard from a player perspective to…
Tim Sackton: generally speaking, red herrings… I mean, I know it wasn't intended to be a red herring puzzle, it was intended to be a vibe and not a puzzle at all, but it functioned like a red herring puzzle.
Kate Sackton: Like, there'.
Tim Sackton: And red herrings basically never work in D&D. Like, you should just never have a red herring.
Tim Sackton: Unless it's a ring of soul trapping that a hag is held, is hiding in.
David S. Kong: I just woke up, what happened?
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, man.
Kate Sackton: Really?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We're debriefing on role-playing game mechanics and…
Tim Sackton: We…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Possibilities.
Tim Sackton: We, we, we navigated through what we eventually learned was essentially a Rubik's cube.
David S. Kong: Week…
Tim Sackton: We got to Rome with an old dwarf who told us about A bunch of stuff.
Tim Sackton: Including some weird mold infection that she's scared of and.
David S. Kong: Oh, but.
Tim Sackton: Oh.
David S. Kong: Other people got infected with. Remember the other people that…
Mike: Yes, yes, she was excited about those people because it.
Tim Sackton: Yes.
Mike: There's some evidence about the mold infection.
David S. Kong: Mmm.
Tim Sackton: Exactly.
Kate Sackton: Apparently…
Tim Sackton: I'm.
Kate Sackton: Into people turning into monsters with mouths in their chest.
Eric Rosenbaum: And it's never…
Tim Sackton: Probably.
Eric Rosenbaum: late.
Tim Sackton: It's.
Eric Rosenbaum: to live.
Tim Sackton: I didn't say this in character, but maybe my character would know this. It's probably what smells bad.
David S. Kong: Yeah, totally.
Mike: Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Fruiting bodies are in the head.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right.
Tim Sackton: Right, so this is what the road guards are guarding against, is this infection.
David S. Kong: Exactly, yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, nice.
Tim Sackton: Bye.
Eric Rosenbaum: Nice.
Tim Sackton: We still haven't figured out how to leave. And then we were talking about the nature of role playing game puzzles and the fact that we all got distracted, especially me, by trying to solve the maze. And so didn't spend any time really investigating the concepts of the room, even though the maze.
Eric Rosenbaum: Exact.
Tim Sackton: It's actually supposed to be unsolvable.
Eric Rosenbaum: Kong, so when you design your, your, Dragonet campaign, make a really complicated.
Mike: It has to have a complicated maze for Tim. Yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: that he cannot solve.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And make it really clear, make it really clear, though, that it has to be solved. Yeah.
Mike: Yeah, yeah. It has to be obvious that the way to solve the adventure is to solve the maze. The maze has to be unsolvable.
David S. Kong: I'm gonna… I'm gonna put… I'm gonna put Tim in a breakout room, and just have him solve a… solve a maze.
Eric Rosenbaum: I can't believe that.
Tim Sackton: You have to be careful. I won't, you know, play in your campaigns. No, of course I'll play in your campaigns.
Tim Sackton: No.
David S. Kong: This is…
Eric Rosenbaum: No, it's good advice though, Tim. It is helpful to try to understand like what works and doesn't as well.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, it's useful to think through it.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And what… what can you do in the setup, and what can you do in the moment?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's helpful for me, anyway.
Tim Sackton: Right.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, I mean…
Tim Sackton: I think over the past five years, I've gotten much better at figuring out what to prep to make the vibe go the way I want. I'm not sure I'm still great at correcting things in the moment that
Tim Sackton: Go off the rails.
Tim Sackton: I usually just let things go off the rails and then try and fix it later.
Tim Sackton: That's how you end up with an entire adventure to get an entire session exploring a tower you were supposed to just fly over.
Tim Sackton: I should have known that would happen.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right.
David S. Kong: Can't put a tower there.
Mike: Got a manual creating columns that we forgot.
Tim Sackton: Which… Yeah.
Tim Sackton: Well, you didn't have time to use.
Mike: Right.
Tim Sackton: It was supposed to be like the seeker make it into the pilot of the ship when it flies off between the planes or something.
Tim Sackton: Anyway, that's for later.
Mike: Right.
Tim Sackton: In any case, we should go to bed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Onwards.
Tim Sackton: We're playing…
Tim Sackton: We're planning again next week, so of course everybody was asleep, so we'll still have to recap the session.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'll work over concession notes. I can probably, I can probably.
Tim Sackton: I can probably get… well, now, you don't have to… they don't have to be brisk, because you can always just click on the short.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's right.
Eric Rosenbaum: Also, just like somebody vibe code a Rubik's Cube.
Eric Rosenbaum: Maze Simulator.
Mike: Yeah.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm on it.
Kate Sackton: No.
Tim Sackton: You should do it, Eric.
Eric Rosenbaum: I know.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): See y'all.
Tim Sackton: Okay, good name.
Mike: Hey, everybody.
Eric Rosenbaum: Hey, guys.